你不用怕啦，它跑不出来的啦
Don't be afraid. It's trapped in a cage!
你为什么要拿老虎大便呢？
Why must you get the tiger feces?
偷渡一定要经过梧桐山
...
梧桐山那里有好多狼狗
There's a lot of wild wolf-dogs down there.
会咬死人的！
They'd definitely bite.
现在有了老虎大便就安了
But with tiger feces, there's nothing to fear
因为那些狼狗闻到老虎大便  跑都来不及
because the wild wolf-dogs would be scared away from the smell of tiger feces.
傻鸡，你的手长
You've got long hands, silly chicken.
伸进去拿些老虎大便出来
Why don't you reach for the feces with your hands?
什么？你要我用手去拿？
What? Stick my hands to fetch this stuff?
你没有听说过…
Like an old saying goes
老虎的屁股是摸不得的
"never touch a tiger's ass".
你自己去拿  算啦…！
...
前进！你去！
Then you go get it, chin chun.
不必麻烦了
Is there any need to go through all that trouble?
拿根竹竿把大便弄出来就行了
Just get a bamboo stick, scoop it out and you'll be set.
收工啦！
My work's done for the day.
为什么呢？
Why?
我这根断掉了，我不干啦
My stick's broken. I give up.
先不要走啦
Don't leave yet.
我看现在是时候了
I think it's time to... Enter the tiger's lair.
深入虎穴
It'd be impossible to fetch tiger feces
不入虎穴，焉得虎屎！  对
if you don't go into the tiger's lair right!
我们用桶挡住
Each of us cover ourselves with a barrel.
就不怕老虎扑过来了
Then we won't prevent ourselves from being attacked by the tiger.
这种锁用根铁丝
Even a wire can fix such a primitive lock.
就可以摆平了
You just need to wiggle it around a little bit. Look!
看我的
Look at me.
开了！
It's opened.
小声一点呀
Don't get too loud.
桶拿好    拿来啦！
- Here! Grab your barrel. - Give it to me!
小心老虎转身啰，来
May the tiger in case it turns around. Come on!
救命呀
- Help!
关门呀…
- Hurry up and shut the gates.
救命呀
Help!
吓得尿都快流出来了
It make me scared to death.
有人来了
Someone's there.
岂有此理，那些人又来偷老虎大便了
God damn it! You guys are here to steal tiger feces again?
别再装模做样了
You can stop pretending now!
哪来那么多老虎大便呀
No tiger takes a shit that often.
要老虎拉那么多大便
Give him some laxatives
除非让它吃泻药
if you have the tiger to defecate.
到哪里去找那么多泻药啊？
Where can we get laxatives?
坏了！不过没有关系
That's bad. But have no fear.
我们的思想早就被武装起来了
We've been long immersed in great thinking.
我们可以用脑
We can use our heads.
就算没有真的泻药
Sure, we don't have any laxatives
我们可以人造泻药
but we can make artificial laxative.
人造泻药？
Artificia! Laxative?
小虎小虎快屙吧
Tiger! Tiger! With your rump...
小虎小虎唔唔唔
Tiger! Tiger! Take a dump!
小虎小虎
Tiger! Tiger!
尾巴翘起来了
It's working! He's wagging his tail.
不知道是要尿尿还是大便
But we don't know if he'll be defecating
继续唱呀…
or urinating. Let's continue.
小虎！小虎！快屙吧！
Tiger! Tiger! With your rump...
小虎！小虎！唔唔唔！  它尿尿了…！继续唱！
Tiger! Tiger! Take a dump! He's leaking water! Let's continue!
小虎！小虎！唔唔唔
Tiger! Tiger! Take a dump...
小心它放臭屁哦
Take a dump...
臭屁不响，响屁不臭
Just in case it blows a nasty fart, be careful.
它的屁是又臭又响
Damn! That tiger's fart stinks! It's so nauseating.
这只老虎肠胃有毛病
He might have intestinal disorder
所以拉稀大便啊
so he may poop out some nasty feces.
怎样把它弄出来
How do we bring it out?
傻鸡
Silly chicken!
你脖子粗，力气大
You're a strong man.
用水管吸出来  好！
Suck it out with a tube. Alright!
小虎快点起来啦
Get up, little tiger!
不要挡住我兄弟吸你的大便啦
Don't stand in my brother's way to pick up your feces.
吸呀！
Suck it up.
吸呀，用力吸呀  怎么都吸不到呢？吸不到呀
I can't seem to suck it no matter how hard I try. I can't do it.
为什么吸不到  为什么吸不到
Why can't you?
要用丹田气呀！像这样…
Use the air from your stomach. Like this!
还是吸不到呀
You can't suck it either.
滚开了，让我来，你看…
Stand aside! Allow me! Watch this.
除了要用丹田之气呀
You have to suck it up by force!
嘴巴也要用力嘛
Suck it harder with your mouth.
你嘴巴好臭啊
Your mouth stinks.
我不管啦，你一定要跟我结婚啦
I don't care!
做我的爱人我才让你走
I'll only allow you to leave as long as you marry me and be my lover.
先做一半都不可以的
No! Not even for a while.
什么叫做一半啊
What do you mean?
做你的爱人当然不可以
I can't be your lover!
跟你做爱更不用谈呀
And don't even carry the thought that we'll ever make love.
你好呀！你想自己一个人  去香港不理我！
That's some nerve you've got! You want to go to Hong Kong and leave me behind.
江青！我去香港买只  Pierre Car双送你！
Jiang qing! Once I go to Hong Kong, the least I can do for you is to buy you a Pierre croissant for you.
不是Pierre Car单吗？
Isn't it a Pierre cardin?
Pierre Car双是Pierre Car  的超级产品
...
更贵哩
It's very expensive.
我要劳力士！
I want a rolex!
我去到香港什么都买给你啦
I'll buy whatever you want once I'm in Hong Kong.
阿伟！阿伟呀…！
Wai! Wai!
好啦！我来数花瓣决定我的命运啦
Alright! I'll decide my destiny by pulling out the flower pedals.
要表，要人…
I want the watch...! Want him...
要表，要人…要表？
The watch... him... the watch... Him... the watch?
我唔要表！我要人！
I don't want the watch. I want him!
我要去检举他！
I must stab his back!
港币！波胆！
Hong Kong dollars, cakes, biscuits...
江苏饼！葡萄糖！
Glucose, beef jerky...
牛肉干！菜干！
Dried vegetables, rice cake...
炒米饼！万宝路香烟！
Marlboro cigarettes! Hmmm... That's about it.
唔！差唔多啦！
Hey! Don't drink too much bamboo juice!
你不要喝那么多竹叶青呀？  好伤的！
It's bad for your stomach.
你煮多点东西给我吃啦
Then, make some more for me!
我怕我饿死都没到香港
I don't want to starve myself before I reach Hong Kong.
你不是去喝酒呀！是去偷渡呀！
You're not there for drinking. You're immigrating there illegally.
你去到香港，记得同我买洗碗机
Once you get to Hong Kong. Remember to buy me a dishwasher
仲有微波炉，我要乐声牌架！
and don't forget to buy a panasonic microwave for me.
去到再说吧！  当然啦
Only if I get there! Of course!
想谋杀呀？
What is this? Murder?
吓得我呀！进来啦！
What a scare! Come in!
干妈！     乖哦
- Godmother! - Good boy
准备这么多东西哦？
wow! You've prepared so much.
我当然有准备啦！
Of course!
我们来平均分配一下！
Let's split it all equally!
炒米饼我的！番薯饼给你
Rice cakes? Mine! You can take my naval biscuits.
葡萄糖给我！红糖给你！
Glucose? Mine! You can take my brown sugar.
牛肉干给我！菜干给你！
Beef jerky? Mine. Okay! Here's some dried vegetables for you.
你是在平均分配吗？
It's great stuff. You call this equal splitting?
你偷啦！…
This is more like a robbery! Are you a crook?
我们是好兄弟啦！
We're brothers.
我另外有样好东西给你啦
I'll share some of the good stuff for you.
不要啰哩啰嗦
Don't gripe!
这是给你的
It's for you.
算你还有良心啦
Now, that's better.
这是什么东西啊，那么臭！
Let's see what this is.
还给我…好东西啊
...
这些是老虎大便加上面粉
This is tiger feces mixed with flour.
才会变成这个样子，你看一下…
That's how you make it look spheric. Look at it.
来…给我…  你还原得蛮像的
I'll show it to you first.
要分成三份，三份
We'll divide this into 3 portions.
你放心啦，我会给你的啦
Since I can bring it over here, I will divide it to you guys.
拿把菜刀来啦  快
Get me a knife first.
你们每人一条啦，这条是我的
One for each of you. This one is mine.
为什么我们这条那么小
Why is mine so tiny?
你那条那么大
Why is yours so huge?
当然啦，用面粉炸的
Well, of course! I deep-fried this with flour.
面粉不用花钱呀
Flour isn't free.
炸完之后我的锅也报销了
The wok isn't useable once it's been used.
你们嫌臭…是不是？
It stinks. Do you want it? Do you want it?
不要…还我…
If you don't want it, give it back!
我不要啦，炸过更臭啦
I don't want it! It still smells after being deep-fried.
真热闹呀？去旅行呀？
Pretty rowdy, aren't we? Going on a tour?
干妈，是朱同志呀
Godmother, this is comrade zhu!
芙蓉镇的朱笃背同志
Comrade zhu du-bei from the city of furong.
笃背同志
Comrade du-bei.
不是，是朱主任啦，朱主任
No! It's superintendent zhu.
朱主任    朱主任
- Superintendent zhu! - Superintendent zhu!
这是什么？球胆？
What's this?
不是啦，我们三个要去打球啦  对啊，打球啦
No! We were just going to go out and play some ball. Yeah! Play ball!
葡萄糖，增强体力
Glucose... to increase your physical vigor?
是前进他身体不好，用来补身体的  对…
Oh!
我头晕啦  坐…
- There's stars circling my head. - Sit down!
港币？去香港？
Hong Kong dollars? Going to Hong Kong?
港币…给你补身的！
Hong Kong dollars... for your nourishment.
好极好极！年青有为！爱国！
Splendid! So young and full of potential. Very patriotic!
他妈的，老虎大便？
God damn! Tiger feces?
他身体不好，给医生化验的，你看！
So we have to take this to the doctor for an inspection. Take a look!
我前两天屙血呀！
I defecated blood a couple of days ago.
胡说八道！
...
彩电！
A color TV.
彩电他也要呀
You even want the color TV?
我怀疑你们要利用这部彩电
I suspect you boys intend to use this color TV
漂到香港去
to drift yourselves over to Hong Kong.
我要把这个带回去研究研究！
I must take this back to investigate.
还有，这些也要带回去研究
Furthermore, I must take all of this back for investigation.
你大小通吃呀！  包…
Wrap it up!
全包起来！    快
Set everything in there. Quickly!
我们全部放进去呀！
We're setting everything in.
快     快…
- Hurry up! - Hurry up...
全都是你的了！慢慢走！
Yes! It's all yours now. Take care!
好，我一踏去这个门口
Once I step out this door,
就将你地满脑子偷渡的思想  忘记得一干二净！
I shall completely forget your dirty thoughts of illegal entry into Hong Kong.
你们放心吧！
Don't you worry about that!
是谁想偷渡？
Who dares to venture illegal entry?
是他！
It's him!
连你都一起带走！
...
你们弄错啦     冤枉呀！
- I have nothing to do with this. - I'm innocent!
走         冤枉呀…
- Go! - I'm innocent!
把她捉去枪毙
Take her out for execution. Execute her!
少说废话啦
Why are you still speaking in mandarin for?
准备明天出发啦，走
We'd better prepare for our journey tomorrow.
我又伤风又鼻塞！高佬！
I've got a cold and a nasal conjestion.
你有没有东西吃呀？
Don't you have any food to eat, beanstalk?
你自己也有干粮
Didn't you bring any dried food for yourself?
我的吃完啦，你还有没有啊
I ate it all. Do you still have any?
谁叫你不停地吃，没有啦
No one told you to eat from day to night. I've got nothing left!
当然啦，你好像去野餐一样
Well, of course! You ate like you were having a picnic.
什么都没有啦
You've eaten everything since you've been eating the whole day.
我又冷又饿，恐怕到不了香港啦
I've starving so much. I'm afraid I can't make it to Hong Kong.
全被你吃光了，没有啦
You ate everything. There's nothing left.
你答应我妈妈要照顾我的啦
Didn't you promise my mother that you'll take care of me?
你把背包拿过来给我看看还有没有
Give me your backpack. Let me see if there's anything left.
不信哦，不信你自己看
Take a look for yourself if you don't believe me.
发财啦，还有这么大一块榴莲糕
Perfect! There's a big durian cake.
你还想骗我
Even with a nasal conjestion, I can take it.
这口味好重啊，勉强地吃了
The flavor's so strong. I'll take it for now.
狼狗！
A panther!
傻鸡快起来，狼狗来了
Silly chicken, get up! There's a big panther!
前进起来啦，快点…  起来啦
Chin chun, get up! Chin chun!
我们往哪里去？
...
快点…    我戴眼镜呀
- Hurry up! - Pick up your glasses!
放狗！
- Unleash the dogs!
趴下
- Lie down!
老虎大便呢？
Where's the tiger feces?
大便到哪里去了？
Where's the shit?
好臭啊，我知道了
It stinks! I know where it is.
被你吃掉了
You ate it.
你怎么连老虎大便也吃呀
Why did you eat the feces?
人家昨天晚上肚子饿嘛
Well, I was hungry.
快走呀
Let's go!
怎么办呀？
What do we do?
兵分三路！
We'll split three ways. Go away!
走开！不要咬我！
Don't bite me! Go away!
高佬伟！高佬伟！
Beanstalk wai! Beanstalk wai!
你不要管我！你自己走啦！
Don't mind me! Get out of here!
不要管我，快走呀
Go! Quickly!
高佬伟！
Beanstalk wai!
不是我啦，它啦…
It's not me! It's him.
傻鸡      高佬！前进
Beanstalk! Chin chun!
傻鸡，不要过来
Don't come over, silly chicken!
妈呀！
Mommy!
傻鸡快走呀
Get out of here!
救命呀…
Help!
弄点真气给我啦…  救命呀…
- Pass some of your breath to me! - Help!
怎么弄呀
How do I do that?
闭住嘴巴，保留真气
Close your mouth to keep your breath.
手伸过来…
Then, stretch your hand over to me!
救命呀…
Help!
狼狗来了     狼狗来了
Help!  The panther's coming!
双剑合壁！
Two sword combination!
好棒…
Bravo!
胜利啦…
I won!
胜利啦！你怎么啦？
I won! What are you doing?
把送料袋拿出来
...
天一黑，我们就要下水
一直往前游，天亮之前一定要到香港
and swim towards the shore. We'll swim over to Hong Kong before dawn.
否则大家完蛋
Otherwise, we'll be in a lot of trouble.
天那么黑，很容易走丢的
It'll be easy for us to be lost when it's dark outside.
所以哦，大家要记住
That's why we've got to remember this
蔡大哥约我们在那一家
...
大角嘴半岛茶餐厅见面
peninsula cafe in tai kok tsui.
什么茶餐厅，什么嘴呀？
What cafe again?
有茶喝，有自助餐吃，还有歌听
They serve tea and buffet meals accompanied with music.
大角嘴半岛茶餐厅
It's the peninsula café located at tai kok tsui.
我早就知道你们会忘记呀
...
所以我写了两张地址
I've already written down the address.
一人一张，千万要记住哦
One for each of you. Keep it well with you.
不要弄丢了，小心点
You better be there! Keep it with you!
记不记得我们的暗语  记得
Do you remember our code? Yes...
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达！
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达！
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达！
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
顺顺利利直到大角嘴，香港见！
...
香港见！    香港见！
See you in Hong Kong.
这么多贝壳，真是要人命呀
So many oyster shells! Trying to kill people here?
回头再看一看我美丽的家乡
Let's look at our beautiful motherland once more.
糟了，跟高佬傻鸡他们失散了
Damn! I've lost beanstalk and silly chicken.
怎样跟他们汇合呢？
How am I going to meet up with them?
不用怕，我有地址
Oh yeah! Nothing to fear. I've still got the address.
半岛？还有半张怎么不见了？
Peninsula! Damn! I've only got half of the address.
怎么这家半岛通通写英文字呀
Wow! Why is there only english in this peninsula?
好豪华哦
It looks so grand!
六尺三呼叫控制室
6 foot 3, calling control.
我是香港人，我有身份证呀
...
大狼狗
Panther! Panther!
不要咬我，救命呀…
Don't unleash it! Please don't unleash it. Put it away!
原来是狗的展览会呀
A dog exhibition!
这是女代表，好漂亮
A female representative for the dog exhibition? She's so pretty.
红色丝袜红色鞋
Red stockings and red shoes!
比刘晓庆还漂亮
She's prettier than liu xiao-qing.
还有名车哦
Wow! She's even got a fancy car!
香车美人
Wow! A real beauty in a fancy car!
他在跟我笑
She's staring at me.
小姐，不要这样，我会害羞的
Please don't poke me, miss! I'm shy.
你干什么？过来…  我以为是女代表
What are you doing? Come here! I thought it was the representative.
你到这里来找谁呀
Whom are you looking for?
高佬伟约我来这里喝咖啡
I've got a meeting with beanstalk wai for a coffee.
基佬伟？
- Beanstalk wai? - Gay wai!
基佬伟！     高佬伟！
It's wai.
来…他找基佬伟，带他从后面进去
He's looking for gay wai. Take him in from the back door
这个人是来找基佬伟的
he's looking for gay wai.
你带他进去吧
Take him in.
跟我来啊   谢谢
...
大家好…  你站在这里干什么？快走呀
Hello! Hello! What are you standing here for? Keep walking.
大家好
Hello, everybody!
都是给你吃的
...
这么多鸡屁股怎么吃得完？
How can I eat this entire chicken's behind.
吃鸡补鸡嘛
It's good for your behind too. Just eat it!
我这里有香烟  这里禁止抽烟
- I've got cigarettes. Want some? - We don't allow cigarettes here.
快吃呀！
Eat it!
马上就来了
...
Honey！Hellosweetie
Honey! Hello, sweetie!
你怎么摸我屁股啊
Why did you grab my ass?
Honey！你是不是西洋仔介绍你来的
Hey there, honey! Were you recommended by a westerner to come over here?
是高佬伟约我来的
I've got a meeting with beanstalk.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
你的名字好脏哦！
...
你刚才是不是吃了很多鸡屁股？
刚才那个人给我吃了  二十个鸡屁股
That four-eyed kid just gave me over twenty chicken buttocks to eat.
二十个！Very good！  不要摸我屁股啊
- Twenty! Very good! - Don't touch my ass!
我很敏感啊，我会放屁  Come on honey，I like you
- Come on honey, I like you. - I'm very sensitive! I'll fart!
不要啦
Please don't!
Where are you go？Come back！
Where are you go? Come back!
救命呀，腐败的资本主义呀
Help! Decadent capitalism!
场面好大，好像要开大会
Wow! It looks so grand. Almost like the people's congress.
人家说香港遍地是黄金
Wow! They say Hong Kong is filled with gold.
原来是真的
So what they say is true!
不要太贪心，一瓶就够了
Don't get greedy. Take the medium-sized plate first.
高佬
Beanstalk!
蔡老大，你是怎么搞的
What took you so long, villain kien?
迟到这么久，害我等你半天
I had to cool off my heels for ages!
我都快急疯了
....
讲好了三个怎么只有两个？
Didn't you say there were 3 of you? Why is there only 2 here?
我们还有一个兄弟在海里面失散了
One of our brothers got lost ashore.
这张你的，这张你的
Here! This is yours and this is yours.
这根本不像我嘛
It doesn't look like me at all.
我这一张更糟糕啦
Mine's even worse.
简直就跟女人一样啦
It looks so feminine.
对了，我兄弟那一张呢？
What about my brother's card?
见了面我就给他
I'll give it to him once I see him.
最近条子盯得我好紧
The cops have been on my tail lately.
就这样啊，我走了  等等，先把那一张给我嘛
That'll be it for now. I'm out of here! Wait! Can't you give us the third card?
不要客气呀  各位谢谢光临
Go and have a drink. Help yourselves!
多喝点酒呀  多喝点酒呀，谢谢…
Have drinks... thanks. Come over here. I have something to say to you.
你过来，我有话跟你说  好…
Ok.
你好    你好…谢谢
Hello - hello... thank you
我听那些三八婆说
those gossipers have been saying that
Lychee跟上官飞凤
lychee and fei-feng
是社交界的绝代双娇是不是真的？  是呀…
is perfect couple of the social world is it true? Yes! Yes!
她们可是专门玩弄男人的
They say they specialize in toying with men.
她们会不会耍你呀
Would they toy around with you?
怎么会呢？这么大的场面
No way! How would they toy around
那怎么到现在还不来呢
...
你知道，这个女人遇到大的场面
Well, you know how it is with women!
都要化一点妆的嘛
They take their time with cosmetics and make-up.
你看，她们来了
See? Here they come!
Lychee，这是我大姨妈
Lychee, this is your aunt.
你好
Hello.
多谢，
Thank you.
找位子坐呀
Why don't we get seated?
这两个三八可真嚣张
Those two bitches are really cocky!
各位来宾，今天是施大嘴的订婚之喜
Ladies and gentlemen, today is the engagement party of big mouth sze.
是我跟Lychee的订婚之喜
It's my engagement with lychee.
我现在代表Lychee请施大嘴上来
As a representative of lychee, I welcome big mouth
问他几个很严重的问题好不好呀
to ask a few serious question. Is that alright?
好…
Yes! Yes!
你只可以回答是或不是
You may only answer yes or no.
你是不是很爱Lychee呀
Are you really in love with lychee?
你是不是第一眼看见她  就很想追她呀
...
你有没有到处跟人家说
我们姐妹俩拼命在追你
we are both chasing for you?
那天晚上我是喝醉了
I was drunk that night.
你只可回答是或不是
You may only answer yes or no.
是…
Yes.
那我们现在请Lychee小姐上来
Then, I'll invite Ms. lychee over
为我们表演一个节目
to the stage for a performance.
施大嘴，你可以下去了  好…
Big mouth sze, you may step off the stage now. Fine
今天，我想为大家表演朗诵！
I would like to recite for you tonight.
好…！
Great!
是施大嘴写给我的情书
It's a love letter that big mouth sze wrote to me.
啊！我愿投在你的怀抱
I want to throw you into my arms.
啊！我愿变成你的内衣裤
I wish to become your underwear
每天贴在你的身上
stick to you everyday
变成你的哈巴狗
and become your slave dog.
躺在你的脚丫里
I shall rest on your toes and
轻舔你的小脚趾
lick your big toe.
你没有权利把我写的情书  公开来让大家听
There's no reason for you to be reading out my love letters out in the public.
你敢写，就不怕人家念啦
Why worry about it being read out loud if you weren't afraid to write it?
今天是我们的订婚日子
Today's our engagement party.
你不要糗我了
Don't embarrass me!
你有没有搅错？谁跟你订婚？
Sorry! But who said I would be engaged to you?
你那天答应跟我订婚
You promised to marry me on the day I proposed to you.
叫我发请帖给我所有亲戚朋友
You even told me to send out invitations to my family and relatives.
你不晓得那天是四月一号吗？
Don't you know it's the 1st of April?
我看你真是没有幽默感
Some people just don't have a sense of humor.
连愚人节都不记得了
They can even forget about April fools day.
你们摆明耍我？
Are you kidding with me?
今天我没有耍你
Today, I'm not kidding around with you.
那天我才是耍着你玩的
But I was kidding around with you on that day.
帮帮忙赶快跟我订婚吧
Do me a favor and stay engaged to me.
飞凤呀，他中了我们的圈套啦
Fei-feng, he's completely fallen into our trap.
那么那天你在小雅订的衣服
The dress you ordered
就都属于我的了
at Joyce now belongs to me.
对了，你真行呀
That's right! You're smart!
你们拿我打赌？
You took me for a bet?
我们姐妹俩他也敢糗
So he's got guts to sling mud at us.
你看看，亏我对你一片痴心
Look at this! And to think that I've loved you dearly,
你把我当傻瓜
you take me for an idiot!
大姨妈，她们欺负我  大嘴呀，不哭…不要哭
Auntie! Don't cry, big mouth. Don't cry. Stop crying! She's making fun of me!
你们两个，既然不喜欢人家
If you two aren't really serious about him,
就不要玩弄人家嘛，真是的
then don't take him for a fool.
大嘴呀
Big mouth
我是香港人呀
...
我要抓你，走  不要抓我…
- I want to arrest you! - Don't arrest me...
走
Go
不要抓我…    大嘴
- Don't arrest me! - Big mouth.
你这是什么东西呀，怎么那么臭
Big moutht who is this pig? He smells bad!
这就是你送给我的订婚礼物？
So is this your engagement present for me?
你说他哦？      她说你
...
她说你        她说你
- She's talking about you! - She means youl!
我？难道我长得很丑？
So, do I look ugly to you?
你以为你长得漂亮
Bitch! So now you think you're pretty?
我不漂亮吗？
Aren't 1?
很漂亮，还很香
Actually, you are pretty and you smell nice too.
那关你什么事呀
Even if I am pretty, it's none of your business.
全世界的男人死光了
I'd never pick you if you were the last man alive.
我也不会要你
It reeks badly,
Lychee，这个男人臭死了
lychee. Let's leave!
我们走吧  三八你说我嘴巴臭
Bitch! You say that my mouth stinks.
帮帮忙，赶快叫警察  什么事？…
Arrest him! Arrest him!
抓住他们，抓住那些臭男人  我要报仇！
What happened?
Arrest all those stinky men! I want revenge!
我要报仇！  不要抓我
- Don't arrest me!
不要抓我  你们都给我滚，给我走
- You all leave, leave!
我不要你们同情我
I don't need your pity!
你不准走，你跟我来  你听我说…
- You can't leave! Come with me! - Listen to me,
其实我只喝了一瓶竹叶青呀
I only drank some bamboo juice.
只要你跟我合作，有你好处
...
有什么好处呀？
What bonus?
这里好资本主义
This place is so capitalistic!
Anita是本港最有名的形象设计专家
Anita's a very popular image consultant around here in Hong Kong.
劳改我呀！
You'll be reformed into a playboy.
把你变成一个多情公子呀！
...
一、二、三、四、五、
1,2,3,4,5
六、七、八！
6,7,8
二、二、三、四、五、  六、七、八！
2,2,3,4,5,6, 7, 8!
扭一下腰，扭腰，踩地…
Twist your bottom. Stomp the ground...
转身，蹲下
Turn around and squat down
屁股抬高一点，抬高一点
get your bottom down and up!
起立，抬腿
Higher! Spread it wider!
抬高一点，转身，pose
Stand still, turn around and pose.
就你这个样子，怎么当香港小姐呀
How can you be Ms. Hong Kong like that?
怎么跟张曼玉比呀？
How can you compete with pauline yeung?
简直是个猪呀
Just like a pig!
好了不要哭了，我叫你不要哭了
Stop crying. Pipe down this very instant.
Shutup！
Shut up!
要哭，也得要有个仪态
Even when crying, you must have posture.
要哭也得哭得有台风，有美感
You have to cry with poise and give it a sense of beauty.
看着我！
Watch me!
哭一次我看看
Do it once and show it to me.
我不行啦，我做不到
I'm a failure! I'm such a failure!
Anita，又在替人家教女儿呀
Anita, you're tutoring that girl for them again?
不许再哭了，进去
Stop crying and get in!
快点进去呀
Go!
我有一个人想交给你训练
I have someone I'd like you to train.
我要你把他训练成社交界的  第一号多情公子
I want you to turn him into a playboy in society.
气死Lychee跟飞凤
Let him lure lychee and fei-feng into
好泄我心头之恨呀
a prank to vent out my feelings.
我要给他做个测验
I'd like to conduct a test on him.
通过测验我才考虑教他
Once he passes, I can consider him.
你尽管试好了
- Then, please test him out.
身材不错
- He's pretty well built.
你现在把我当成你一生中  最喜欢的女人
Now, pretend that I am the woman that you love.
你对我说一句话，让我跟你上床
Say something to convince me to sleep with you.
你说呀
Say it!
我…我怕不行呀
L... I'm afraid that I'll screw it up.
你本来就不行
Huh? You're already screwed.
这又什么关系呢？赶快说嘛
You can't get any more screwed than that. Just say it.
不行啦     为什么？
- I can't. - Why not?
难道你以前都没有跟女人上过床呀
Haven't you slept with women at your age?
有，跟我妈啦
I have but with my mother.
你不要装处男啦
Stop pretending to be a virgin.
我们那不流行上床
We never do that.
被人家发现会被枪毙
We get executed if people find out that we did that.
我们流行打野外
We only play in the field.
好！我们就打野外
Very well! Then seduce me to play in the field.
说呀！
Say it!
只能说一句？  一句太少了
Just one sentence? Is that all?
走，去办事
Hey! Let's get humped!
就这么一句啊
That's it?
不然怎样？行就行，不行就算了
What else is there? If it works, it works. If it doesn't, then forget it.
好！直接，简单，干脆，自然啊  谢谢
Bravo! Direct! Simple! Clear out! Natural! Thank you!
我再问你，如果你想甩掉我
I'll ask you again. If you wanted to dump me,
跟我说三句话要打发我走
give me three sentences to make me leave.
三句？
Three sentences?
说呀！
Say it.
三句太少了，加两句怎么样？
Three may be too little. How about adding another two?
我说三句
Three sentences will do.
你好丑！你好丑！你好丑！
You're a nut! You're a nut! You're a nut!
朱丽丽
Lily chu!
够绝情够火候呀
That's well determined and perfectly executed!
十、九、八、七、六、
10,9,8,7,6
五、四、三、二、一！
5,4,3,2,1
Ta姐！什么事呀？
What's the matter, madame Anita?
跟他接吻！
Kiss him!
她干什么？发骚呀？
What's she doing? A turn-on?
作为一个真正的花花公子
As a real playboy,
是不会犹豫去吻任何一个女人的
you wouldn't hesitate to kiss any women.
你用你认为最温柔
Now, kiss her in what you believe is the
最能够令女人动情的方法去吻她
most gentlest way to get her turned on.
做好准备
Be prepared!
我不是随便的男人
...
去呀
Just do it!
我有什么好处？
Do I get anything out of this?
你吻她，你吻完之后我请你吃馄饨面
Just kiss her! I'll buy you wonton noodles after you kiss her.
真的？两碗哦
Really? Two bowls?
表妹，你要小心呀
Take care, cousin!
够不够悍啊？
Aren't you damned yet?
好棒啊，她都快晕倒  起来了
Bravo! You've kissed her till she passed out. Get up!
好臭，他有口臭  好啦
It stinks! He has bad breath!
怎么样？他还不错吧
Get going.
你叫我把这种垃圾变成  第一号花花公子
So you want me to turn this thing into a playboy?
你以为Nina Lychee跟上官飞凤  会喜欢他吗？
Do you think Nina lychee and fei-feng would ever like him?
拜托！没想像力，没水准
What a waste of time! He's got no imagination, no manners
没有男人原始的性魅力
and not an ounce of primitive male appeal.
他简直就不是男人
He's practically not a man at all!
你说什么？你说够了没？
What did you say? Are you finished yet?
Never yell at me！
Never yell at me!
这个世界只有你最棒
...
只有你懂得盖蚊帐
No one is as educated as you are.
别人有一点缺点就踩人家
You belittle me because I'm deficient in some way.
我懂的你不见得懂呀
I'm more educated on things that you don't know.
香港人都有自大狂呀
You Hong Kong people are arrogant!
广西的东边是哪里呀
...
就是广东
Guangdong!
山西的东边是哪里呀  山东
What's east of shanxi? Shangdong.
错！是河北
Wrong! It's hebei.
湖南的北边是哪里呀
What's north of hunan?
我知道，不会是湖北
I'm pretty sure it's not hubei.
哈哈…就是湖北！
Haha! But it is hubei!
陕西的东边是哪里  陕东
- Where is east of shensi - Shento
笑死人啦！还闪电呢
oh man! You're making me laugh here!
中国哪有什么地方叫陕东
There's no such province in China called shendong.
不过我也不会笑你孤陋寡闻
But I won't belittle you for your ignorance.
你以后也不可以再侮辱我了
So you better not insult me as well.
因为我是龙的传人
Because I'm a descendent of the dragon!
我有我的自尊啊
I have dignity so I won't yell at you two!
以后不理你们两个人了
...
你当我是猪呀
你们这两个资本主义的败类
The two of you are riffraffs to capitalism.
在这里给我反省反省
Think about it!
前进…
Chin chun!
我想吃馄饨面
I want to eat some wonton noodles.
Anita我把他叫回来跟你道歉
Anita, I'll ask him to apologize to you.
不用了，如果他想回来
There's no need for that! If he wants to come back,
早晚会回来的
then he'll return by himself
如果他不想回来，逼他也没用
if he doesn't want to come back, then it's useless to force it out of him.
前途茫茫，要到哪里去？
It's so windy and rainy right now. Where else can I go?
还有半张呢
Where's the other half?
找到了，半岛茶餐厅！
There it is! Peninsula cafe!
我又摆乌龙了
Tai kok tsui!
计程车
Ta... taxi!
钱用光了
There goes all my money.
半岛茶餐厅
The peninsula cafe!
大生意…
...
傻鸡跟高佬一定会来
I'm sure silly chicken and beanstalk will come.
我等，我等啊
I'll wait. I'll wait!
从上面那个出口跑到下面这个出口
...
这样跑来跑去也不是办法呀
We should something more effective rather than walking back and forth.
我们再到前面的出口看看
Then, we'll go through another hole.
我们总要想办法填饱肚子呀
We don't have any money!
哪有钱呀！刚才坐计程车都坐光了
We've spent it all on the taxi.
我们干脆学前面那对夫妻那样
How about we perform for money like that old couple over there?
一个吹口琴，一个吹萧好了
One's playing the harmonica, the other is playing the flute.
他们表面的行为是卖艺
As apparent as this is, they are making a living through the arts.
其实他们真正是在要饭
However, they are actually begging for money.
我才不干这种事情呢
...
也许我们可以换个方法
Or perhaps we can modify a method.
试试看抢劫呀  抢劫？
We can try robbery. Robbery?
高佬，你现在不是在抢劫
...
简直是没有人格的行为呀  少啰嗦啦
Don't gripe!
高佬，现在我们怎么办
Beanstalk, what do we do now?
进去躲一躲
Let's hide in here!
抢劫呀，有人抢劫呀  人不见了
It's that way!
抢劫啊？哪里抢劫呀
Robbery? Where?
你们两个做什么？不要走呀
- What are you doing? - Wait!
高佬，傻鸡
Beanstalk! Silly chicken!
你们做大生意也不找我  前进…
Why didn't you wait for me for the big opportunity?
等我一下，忘记了我的鞋呀
Let me get my shoes first.
你们俩不要跑那么快呀
Wait for me, beanstalk!
快一点呀
Hurry up!
我好想念你们呀
I missed you guys!
我们也好想你呀
I missed you too.
我刚吃了两个蛋挞
...
快一点啊，来不及了
- Hurry up!
把手伸出来
- Stretch your arm over here!
等等我呀
- Wait for me!
等等我呀   快一点啊
- Hurry up! - Wait for me!
把手伸出来
Stretch your arm over here!
快点…
- Hurry up!
我们又重逢啦
We meet again.
我们做大生意为什么不等等我
Why didn't you wait for me when you're going for the big opportunity?
我们也不知道你在哪里  对呀
How did you expect us to know where you are? Exactly!
大生意…
Big opportunity...
这个没什么搅头啦
It's just pocket change!
怎么这么少
- Why is there so little? - Pocket change is good enough.
有比没有好啦
If we had guns, we would have already
如果我们有枪的话就可以  做笔大生意
gone for that big opportunity.
你为什么不买枪呀
Why didn't you buy any guns?
这些钱只够买把水枪呀，傻瓜！钱呢？
This pocket change is only enough to buy a water gun. Where's the money, you numbskull?
到哪里去找钱？
Where would we get it?
你都没脑子的
You've got no brains.
有钱人
The rich guy.
有个有钱人要训练我
...
训练我啊
不是啦，前面那一句
Not that! The one before that.
有钱人啊
The rich man?
有钱人？你怎么到现在才讲
A rich man? Why didn't you mention that earlier?
我们不要管他，去找有钱人
Let's leave him alone. Let's go look for this rich man.
我千辛万苦地求到Anita教他
I've had much difficulty to re-convince Anita to train him.
可是你们一定要把他搅定才行啊
But you must make him obedient.
行啊！有钱什么都行啊
Not a problem! With money, there's always obedience.
他要多少钱
How much does he need?
五万块一个月，外带他的吃住
$50,000 per month including food and living expenses.
连我的女朋友也要一起照顾
...
没问题
No problem!
高佬，情况如何
What's the situation, beanstalk?
你先吃点东西啦
Eat something first!
我终于完全地搅定了
I've finally got it all handled.
我用不怕牺牲，排除万难
With the might that allowed me to overcome all fears and obstacles,
针锋相对，鱼蚌相争的精神
and from the hands of this capitalistic pig,
终于被我在这个万恶的资本家手里
I've managed to fight for
争取到五百块一个月
$500 per month!
吓？怎么只有五百块
Only $5007?
关你屁事啦
It's none of your business!
实在委屈你了
I feel sorry for you.
在这么坏的环境下
you've managed to fight for $500.
你能争取到五百块一个月
It's very hard to achieve that.
已经很不错啦
I should be feeling sorry for you instead.
实在太委屈你了
...
为了我们的大生意
你一定要留下来
you must stay here.
我们出去招兵买马
We'll head out to recruit our troops!
然后第一件事就是对付那个施大嘴
Then, the first thing we shall do is to deal with this big mouth sze.
然后我再回来跟你一起发大财
Then, we'll return to you with more opportunities.
发大财…    发大财
Opportunities!
前进，看着我的眼睛
Look at me, chin chun!
记住，我们是新移民
Remember this. We're newly landed immigrants.
一定要赢    一定要赢
- We can't fail. - We can't fail!
我们要拿光他全部的钱
We must earn all of their money!
钓光他们的马子
Take all their women!
要光他们的马子  吃光他们的饭
Eat every one of their meals.
吃光他们的饭
Eat all of their meals!
好，我们走
Alright then! We're leaving now.
你们真的要走？
...
我舍不得离开你们
I'm going to miss you guys.
好了…没事了，你们俩先走
Okay! Okay! Everything's fine now. You two can go now.
高佬       没事啦
- Beanstalk... - Work hard! Take care.
高佬…    努力！
- Beanstalk - Chin chun!
前进
- Chin chun...
高佬！高佬！  高佬！ ，你有没有怎么样？
Beanstalk. Are you okay, beanstalk?
高佬！你有没有怎么样啊
Are you okay, beanstalk?
努力！努力！
Work hard! Work hard!
我也先走了
I'm leaving now.
不好意思，那天晚上惹你生气
I'm sorry for offending you last night.
希望你能原谅我
I hope you'll forgive me.
我想你现在应该先洗个澡
I think it's time you should go talk a shower.
救命啊！好痒啊！
Ouch! Please don't. That hurts. Help!
发达啦
Wow! We're rich!
干什么？…人家吃冰淇淋  为什么打我？
I'm eating ice cream here. Why did you just hit me? That hurts.
痛死
I'll give you a little tongue twister.
我们来玩绕口令
If you can repeat after me,
我怎么讲你就跟着我怎么讲
then you've earned the right to finish your food.
干什么？
Really?
学绕口令可以纠正你的乡音
The tongue twister is there to fix your chiu chow accent.
董骠中了镖，阿苗学吹萧
...
阿苗学吹萧，骠苗约了沙尘超
Milly made his silk, Billy & Milly met up with Willie
一起喝花雕，然后买马票
to eat some chow kwei diu, and to buy their double q.
阿超好嚣张，气得董骠似火烧
Willy's cocky attitude is lame, bursting Billy into flames.
拿起花雕泼阿超，不准买马票
Billy poured his plate of chow kwei diu on Willy and refused to buy his double q
阿超立刻要撒娇，不要打阿超
...
董骠闪了他的腰，气得阿苗发高烧
Billy slipped and hurt his hips, making it hard for miu to stay still.
什么骠啊，苗，超，什么超…
Chiu... miu... miu... q...
我懂了，骠，苗，超，你吃我香蕉  不许笑
Stop laughing!
做个真正的公子
A playboy must have proper eating
就要懂得吃西餐
etiquette with European food.
吃西餐就要懂得配酒
It is also imperative to know how to match your food with wine.
吃红肉呢，就配红酒
Red meat goes with red wine.
白肉呢，就配白酒
White meat goes with white wine.
羊肉牛肉，就是红肉
Muttons and beef is red meat.
鱼呀，虾呀，螃蟹呀
Fish, lobsters and crabs are
就是白肉
considered to be white meat.
那老虎是什么肉呢
Then, how about tiger meat?
算是红肉！
It's considered to be red meat.
应该配红酒啊
...
哪来这么多老虎大便啊
我吃过整条的，真的
I've eaten an entire piece of tiger feces!
红酒的种类，是分有很多种的
There are many types of red wine.
干什么，猜拳呀
What's going on? A drinking game?
喝掉这两杯酒
Drink these 2 glasses of wine.
看看味道有没有不同
Do you see any difference in its taste?
你叫我猜我就猜
You're smart and I'm smart too.
我还是喜欢竹叶青
But I still prefer bamboo juice!
干什么关灯啊
Why turn off the lights?
打野外呀
Are we making out?
为了方便你学，  我已经注有中文译音了
of its proper pronunciation is also provided.
好大台彩电呀！
That's a big color TV!
Chateau Lafit
Chateau laufit
chateau laufit
Chateau Cheval
chateau cheval
Cheteau Latour
chateau latour
Chateau Margauo
chateau margauo
Pouilly Fuisse
pouilly fuisse
Po…
po...
Fuck！Shit！…
Fuck! Shit! Shit!
作为一个花花公子
To be a playboy who needs to attract
要吸引一个不认识的女人
a girl whom you've just met,
当然最厉害的武器就是笑
the greatest weapon to use in that situation is your smile.
笑给我看
Show me your smile.
把嘴巴擦干净，再笑一次
Wipe your mouth and smile again.
我笑得潇不潇洒呀
Is my smile presentable?
如果你的笑跟猪比起来呀
If the laughter of a pig is considered
那猪笑得都比你潇洒
to be presentable, then I can say you are presentable enough.
笑分很多种的
There are many types of smiles.
最厉害的那种笑，是冷笑
The most popular type is the cold smile.
还有，是微笑
Then, we have the narrow smile.
还有是奸笑
The sly smile.
还有大笑
And also, the broad laughter
阴阴地笑
the chilly smile.
淫笑
The obscene smile.
挑逗性的笑
The seductive smile.
最后这种笑是狂笑
Last but not least, the wild laughter.
从头笑一次给我看
Show it to me from the beginning.
我笑得快没气了
I've smiled myself out of breath.
我恐怕笑不出来
I'm scared that I won't be able to control myself.
冷笑
Cold smile...
微笑
narrow smile...
苦笑
Bitter smile...
大笑
broad smile.
阴阴地笑
Chilly smile...
淫荡地笑
Seductive smile.
好开心的笑
Laugh happily! Stop laughing.
我数到十你立刻就不准笑了
Stop laughing immediately as soon as I count to 10.
十、九、八、七、六、
10, 9, 8, 7, 6,
五、四、三、二、一！
5,4, 3,2, 1!
下一课我教你kiss
Now I'll teach you how to kiss.
Kiss！？什么叫kiss？
Kiss? What's a kiss?
Kiss就是接吻！嘴巴擦干净等我
A kiss is when 2 lips touch as a sign of affection. Wipe your mouth and wait here.
笑死人啊！连接吻都要学
Don't make me laugh! Do I really have to learn this stuff?
开始！
Begin!
干什么？亲完萝卜可以亲你呀？
What's that? So do I have to kiss the carrots before I get to kiss you?
亲个你头啊
You wish!
把这两个铜板吸出来
Now suck that coin out of those lips.
不许用手
Hands off.
那怎么吸啊
How do I suck it out?
吸呀
Suck it!
连萝卜都亲不好，还想亲女人
If you can't handle a carrot, how do you expect to deal with a woman?
干嘛？
What are you doing?
你怎么这么不小心嘛
How can you be so careless?
我帮你挖出来啊
I'll get it out for you.
不懂英文呢
It's hard to stand out in upper-class society
就没办法在香港的那些  上流社会立足
when you aren't able to speak english.
所以你一定要学英文
So that's why you must learn to speak english.
我在电视上看过
I've learned english through watching
听歌学英文啊
music videos on television!
傻瓜，听歌可以学英文啊
Don't be silly I if you can learn english through music,
猩猩都会报新闻了
then I'm sure pigs can fly.
跟我学第一个字
Repeat after me. Y-e-s. Yes!
Y-E-S，yes！是的意思
It means positive.
Y-E-S，yes！是
Y-e-s. Yes means positive.
很多人只懂这个字
Many people who only know how to say this word,
已经可以混得很好了
have been very well established.
他们就叫做yes man
These people are called the "yes men".
我好想吃一碗面
So, a, m ” I a...
还有啊
"Yes man"?
第二个字，是do
Our second word is "do".
是做的意思
It means to perform.
Do，做的意思
Do! It means to perform.
对了，这也可以表示愿意
That's right. It also means that you agree to do something.
不干呢，我可以表示I do not
If you give up, you can also say "I won't do"
结婚的时候在教堂，就说I do
when you marry in a church, you would say "I do".
I do
I do!
钱赚够了就可以说我不do了
Once you've made enough money, you can say "I don't have to do it".
我现在最好是不用do
What's best for me to say is "I don't have to do it".
第三个字，Iook
The third word is "look".
Look！Look！
Look! Look!
是看的意思，也可以解释做仪表
It means to see.
你的Iook还不错啦
It can also mean your appearance.
不过可惜，中看不中用
You look good. Unfortunately, you're good for nothing.
Look就是看看
Look means to see.
Love！
- Love!
- "Lut-fu".
是爱的意思
It means love as in
I love you！就是我爱你
"I love you", which means I love you.
I love…
I "lut-fu"...!
Hello！Vincent！
Hello, Vincent!
你回来啦
You came back already?
你帮我买了只古董表啊
You bought an antique watch for me?
Oh！ I love you！
Oh! I love youl!
I love you！
I love you!
你等一下，我们到房里聊好了
Wait a second. I'll talk to you in my room.
我要上去办事情了
...
同志！同志！
Comrade! Comrade!
我叫做Anita！不叫做同志！
My name is Anita, not "comrade".
Ta姐，我好困哦
Anita! I'm getting sleepy.
可不可以睡午觉啊？  No！
Can I go for an afternoon nap? No!
什么叫no啊？  不行
What does that mean? You can't.
唔吔屎
Not a yes.
发达了
Wow! This is great!
先喝个下午茶
I'll have a quick afternoon drink first.
前进！Anita呢？
Chin chun, where's Anita?
在上面do啦！
She's busy upstairs with something to do.
Do？
Do?
那个什么“神”跟她说love
Some fella name "cent" said he'd drop his pants.
她就上去do了！
So she went upstairs to do something.
上面？
Upstairs?
好大只雁呀！
That's a big pigeon!
天边那只呀！
...
那只鸟很大！
You've got a pretty good eye.
Ta姐说我也差不多啦  什么？
Anita said the look of my scrub is pretty big. What?
她说我很不错啦，就是中看不中用
She said I look fine but I'm good for nothing.
想不到Anita是这种人！  Yes！
Never thought Anita was that kind of person! Y-e-si
你今日有没有do过？
did you do anything today?
跟你无关，这是我的私事
Don't pry into my personal business.
我已经好几天没有do了
I haven't done anything for days.
我叫Ta姐跟我do
I asked Anita to do it for me once
她说她不跟我do，她跟别人do
but she said it's unnecessary. Many people do it with her
叫我自己…自己do！
so she told me to do it myself.
我花钱叫你来学这些啊
Did I spend so much money to have you learning these things?
她说不懂得do
She said if you can't do it,
没办法在上流社会立足！
it'll be hard to stand out in upper-class society.
吃我的香蕉啊，接吻啊
...
Do啊，就是这些啦
love, and looks. Stuff like that!
淫妇，上流社会的淫妇
That tramp! What an upper-class tramp!
你说我什么？
Talking about me?
你问他    Ta姐
- Ask him! - Anita
Ta姐，你do完了
Finished doing your thing, Anita?
你挺会活学活用的嘛
You've even made it to practical use.
英文单词以后不可以乱说一通
Be a little more careful with words next time.
尤其是那个do字
Especially with the word "do".
Yes！以后不讲do
Y-e-s! I won't say "do" from now on.
只是说Iook！OK？
I'll only say "look", okay?
好漂亮呀
It looks beautiful! Are we holding a dance party?
做什么？开舞会呀？
This looks fun! This looks fun!
脱衣舞啊
A burlesque!
成功…
你跳    我怎么跳呀
...
你跟着这些脚印跳！
Follow the footprints and dance.
过来！抱紧我的腰
Come here. Hold onto my waist.
手抬起来，把腰挺直，微笑
Raise your arms. Keep your body straight. Smile!
准备！
Get ready!
前进！后退！还原！
Forward! Step. And back.
Quick！
Quick! Quick! Quick!
对不起…    自己跳啦
- Ouch! I'm so sorry! - Now dance by yourself.
我穿鞋子很不自然
I feel uneasy, dancing with shoes on.
我在乡下都没有穿鞋啦
Because back at home, we're accustomed to dance without shoes.
我记得在田里种田都这样  跳来跳去的
Back in the days when we seeded the fields,
没有问题
we would always trample on it like this.
你打算就这样跳吗？
Are you planning to dance like this?
你不觉得我这样很自然？
Don't you think that I look more natural dancing without my shoes?
我觉得我这样跳得好棒哦
Do you think I'm dancing okay now? Doesn't it look better now?
你学不会晚上没饭吃
If you can't dance properly, there will be no dinner for you.
你不要乱来，每天都不给我吃饭
What's wrong with you? You never provide me any dinner!
你自己看着办吧
Well, it's up to you!
一呀，二呀，三呀，四呀，五呀，六呀
1121314151 g!
高佬呀，我好惨呀
...
没有啊，干什么？
No. What's the matter?
没有关系，我帮你要薪水，再见
Tell him that I'm waiting for his pay. That'll be all.
高佬！高佬！
Beanstalk! Beanstalk!
我好想念你跟傻鸡啊
I really miss you and silly chicken.
你们到哪里去了
Where are you guys?
我们在大角嘴金龙饭店
We're at the golden dragon restaurant in tai kok tsui.
大票人马在谈大生意呀
...
大生意有没有我的份呀
Opportunity? When do I get a share?
当然有啦，我现在没空啦
We've left you a spot. That'll be it for now. I'm very busy now.
插我？…我插你们…
Grabbing me, huh? I'll grab some of that too!
我要去大角嘴找高佬
I'll go to tai kok tsui to look for beanstalk.
好舒服啊，不要再弄了
That feels good!
到九龙塘
...
好啊！   我们去九龙塘博命
We're going for a big brawl in kowloon bay.
你不是要跟我去的吗？
Didn't you say you were going with me?
你！吃蕉吧
Bite me!
肥妹我们来划拳吧
Hey, fatty girl! Play a round of Bangladesh with me.
陆小芬…刘文正…
Robert...
刘文正…陆小芬…
Robert... Bangladesh...
高佬！你又说要谈大生意  输了
Beanstalk wai! Didn't you say you were negotiating business?
我正在练功，练得稀饭都没得吃
I can't even get a decent meal while I'm training.
你在这里大鱼大肉
While you're here eating and
过这种资本主义腐败的生活
living the life of a capitalist pig!
你要腐败，我为什么不可以腐败
If you get to live like a pig, why can't 1?
你要腐败，我们一起腐败
If you want to be so decadent, I should get the same rights as well.
我要比你更腐败
I want to be more decadent than you!
我“唯”！“唯”…！
...
你过来，我有话跟你说
Come with me. I'll have a word with you!
对不起，各位大姐哦
Excuse me, ladies.
过来啊  你要回来哦
Did you know that you almost ruined it for us?
你知不知道，你刚才差点死掉？
...
这几个都是十九区大姐大
现在是女权当道
Women reign supreme around here nowadays.
前进，真倒霉啊！现在是女人世界啊
The men? They're just a piece of shit.
左边起林大姐，崔大妈
The women now have a say. From the left, there's ViXen, lam hoi hoi,
女王蜂，还有夜来香啊
big titty and night soil
全部都是了不起的龙头领导人
all of them are leading figures of the plush society.
你刚才的手势很过瘾啊
It seemed like you were having fun with your hand gestures.
黑社会有黑社会的手势嘛
Triads have always had their hand gestures.
连这一点你都不懂啊
This is called signalling.
你说的刘文正高岭风什么意思啊
So who is this Bangladesh and Robert?
他们是男的，所以被摆平啦
I took them down.
你骗我，傻鸡他不在里面啊
You're lying! Silly chicken's not even here.
傻鸡到九龙塘去拼命啦
Silly chicken went for a big brawl in kowloon bay.
傻鸡去拼命
Silly chicken went for a brawl?
你为什么不掩护他？
Why didn't you protect him?
傻鸡
Silly chicken
傻鸡为了掩护我
for the sake of protecting me
不让我被警察抓去
from getting arrested,
已经壮烈地牺牲了
silly chicken... has already made his sacrifice.
傻鸡壮烈牺牲？
Silly chicken sacrificed himself?
你以为只有你一个人受苦？
Do you really think I'm the only one struggling here?
偶尔挨挨饿，你就叫苦连天
Now you're here, whining about a little starvation.
傻鸡为了我们牺牲了宝贵的生命
But silly chicken sacrificed his own life in exchange for mine.
你现在跑了出来，就是半途而废
Now you've given up halfway through your efforts.
我现在已经开始瞧不起你了
I just can't look up to you anymore.
看着我
Look at me.
我不敢啊，我好惭愧呀！
I can't... I'm so ashamed!
好吧，既然你懂得惭愧
Very well! Since you can feel ashamed of yourself,
我就给你一次机会
I'll give you one more chance.
现在回到施大嘴那里去
Now go back to big mouth sze's place
看他有什么贵重物品
and if he has any expensive valuables that you can give me.
全部拿来给我
Another thing,
还有，你每个月五百块钱
your $500 per month
要拿三百块钱出来
salary has to be decreased to $300.
寄到傻鸡家里去作安家费
We need to give some of that money to silly chicken's family.
我不要啦，五百块全部给他
I don't want it! Just give him the $500!
我懂你的心意啊
I know you meant well, silly boy. But you shouldn't do that. You need money too.
傻瓜，这样子不行的
How about this?
人要用钱的，这样好了
...
你多寄一百九十块钱
You can send $190
然后那十块钱你留在口袋里
and keep $10 for yourself. Got it?
可是香港生活水平高
...
好啦，我们彼此心灵相通，对不对
Okay then! We're on common grounds now, aren't we?
你还记得我们的暗号吗？
Remember our code?
来呀，看着我的眼睛
C'mon! Look into my eyes.
你从我眼睛看到什么？
What do you see in my eyes?
傻鸡       来吧
- Silly chicken! - C'mon!
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达！
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
我们要发达！  我们要发达！
"Fight for victory!"
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达！
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
发达…
"Victory!"
鲜虾饺呀！糯米鸡呀！
"Shrimp dumplings! Sticky rice!"
糯米鸡呀！叉烧包！
"Sticky rice! Pork buns!"
还有这个叉烧包！  虾饺呀！基本步！
"There's still some barbecue pork buns!" "Shrimp dumplings! Basic steps!"
还有啊，叉烧包，莲蓉包呀  叉烧包！…
"Revert! Pork buns again! Lotus seed buns” "pork bun!"
基本步啊，叉烧包…
"Break an egg!"
前进…！
Chin chun!
我被你害死啦！
Oh! You're ruining me!
下个月二号是印度基金舞会  港督都会来参加
The Indian funding banquet will be on next Tuesday. The Hong Kong governor will attend as well.
我希望到时候前进能够以  全新的形象出现！
I hope chin chun may attend in his brand new look.
不可能啦，时间上来不及啦
Impossible! Not enough time. He'd still have to go even
来不及也得去啊
if there isn't enough time.
这是个很难得的机会啊
It's a great opportunity for him.
我怕他不争气啊
He could mess it all up.
想办法让他试一试嘛
We'll have to take a risk no matter what.
他撑得下去吗？
Could he manage?
前进，你一定要撑下去啊
Chin chun, you'll have to manage!
等我把蛋清吃掉啦
Let me finish the eggs first.
听着，你要做最后的冲刺
Listen! Make a last ditch effort!
我妈妈说过蛋清最补啊
Mommy says eggs are nutritious.
来，先用你的眼神
Now, first you use your eyes to
去点燃她心里面的欲火
ignite that desirable flame in her heart.
太夸张啦
That's overdone!
我透不过气来了
I can't breathe!
谁叫你带这个的？
Who told you to wear that mask?
他的嘴巴好臭
He has bad breath!
然后用你最原始的男性魅力  去刺激她
Then, use your most primitive masculine charm to provoke her.
你干什么？
What's wrong with you?
你在干什么？
What were you just doing?
太刺激了  闭嘴
- A little too provoking! - Shut up!
我只是叫你亲她而已
I'm telling you to kiss her.
首先呢，是看
...
然后是闻
Then, you hold it
接着是含
and keep in the mouth
最后是吞
and finally, you swallow.
吞啊？      对了
Swallow... yes!
调情也是一样的
This also applies with flirtation.
首先你要看着对方的眼睛
First, you look into her eyes to give her
使对方觉得你很爱她
the impression that you love her.
然后从耳朵一直闻到  她颈子那里
Then, you start sniffing from her ears all the way to her neck.
她的汗味，比我的狐臭还臭
Her sweat smells even worse than my body odor!
多嘴
Nonsense!
接着把她的耳坠轻轻地含住
Then, you gently hold onto her earlobes.
最后，就像要把它吞到肚子  里面去一样
And finally, you get into the gesture of swallowing her up.
你们两个要死了
What's wrong with you two?
你们决定要这样子是吗？
So is this how you two have decided to do it?
我给你们十五分钟的时间
I'll give you 15 minutes.
你们再胡闹下去，每个人十鞭子
If you two intend to fool around again, each of you will get 10 whippings.
表妹，为了我们免受皮肉之苦
Little sister, in order to prevent any physical suffering,
你…你还是将就一点
you... you take care!
大哥，我求求你，你放了我好不好？
I beg you! Just let me go!
她可不是闹着玩的
Her whip is strong.
我来啦…
Here I come!
他马上下来！
Nelson!
Hello！How do you do？
Hello! How do you do?
Thank you！Come down
Sure！
Hello！
Hello.
怎么样
How is he?
表面上看起来不错
From the looks of it, he's doing good
不过我还是要试一试他
but I want to give him a little test.
这样吧，你当她当作Lychee
How about this? Let's pretend that she is lychee.
你请她跳只舞
Take her out for a dance.
No problem！
No problem.
叉烧包呀！糯米鸡呀！莲蓉包呀
Pork buns! Sticky rice! Lotus seed buns!
鲜虾饺，汉堡包呀！莲蓉包呀！
Shrimp dumplings! Hamburgers! Lotus seed buns!
叉烧包呀！叉烧包呀！糯米鸡呀！
Pork buns! Pork buns! Sticky rice.
停！停！  糯米鸡呀！叉烧包呀！
...
这是高尚的社交场合！
This is an event for the upper-class society.
你什么叉烧包，莲蓉包，大包的
What's with the pork buns, lotus seed buns and all the other buns?
好了，过来坐下  过去…
...
周先生，你是干哪一行的？
Mr. chow, what is your profession?
是财经呀！
...
专家
It's finance and economic specialist.
财经专家呀！
...
你既然对日本经济那么熟
Since you're so familiar with Japanese economics,
现在日本东京股市升那么高
what do you think about the uprising of
你又有什么意见
the stock market in Tokyo?
跌…跌…
...
没有道理一直往是升的  分析得不错
It can't keep rising. That's a fairly good analysis.
那以后呢
- How will it be in the future?
继续跌…
- It'll continue dropping.
以后，会一直往下跌
Then... then, the market will continue to fall.
那再以后呢
And then?
再以后？还是会…跌下来啦
And then? Then, it'll keep falling.
我想，跌下来以后
I think... it'll fall down and it'll hurt its spine.
会跌伤这个脊椎骨
Then, it'll need to rub medicinal alcohol.
就要用这个跌打损伤药一直推
...
Anita你怎么教他的
How do you teach him, Anita?
施生，不关Ta姐事的！
...
她教我的东西我不记得了
I couldn't remember all the stuff that she taught me.
这些都是我自己作出来的
I just ad-libbed everything I've just said.
Anything you say shows that you're a country bumpkin.
我看你说的一些话
Just like a piece of shit!
简直就像一坨屎
a piece of shit!
我真的像一坨屎哦？
Do I look like a piece of shit?
你呀，连大便都不如
You're not even worthy to resemble shit!
因为你是个大陆仔
...
你不要随便侮辱我们新移民
Don't insult us new immigrants!
这是我一个人不好
This is merely my own error!
你不要把大家都骂进去了
You shouldn't make sweeing attacks.
你不是新移民，你是个非法移民
> =~ se ceil eee = eae tert ee ee ee ee ee as a ea ns I ee se ier si
印度基金的舞会也不用去了
No need to go to the Indian funding banquet.
我看他连个看门的都不如
You won't even make a convincing Indian!
你开心啦！你高兴啦！你happy啦！
Are you happy now? You can now rejoice yourself
你自由啦！你不必玩了嘛！
now you're happy! Now you're free!
你不要再混了！
Just play as you please. You don't need do this anymore.
Ta姐…我知道错啦！
Anita! Anita! I know I'm wrong.
你打我吧！你骂我吧！
Please! Just hit me! Scold me!
都把它吃光，你不必问我了
Eat it all! You don't have to ask me anymore.
Ta姐，你不要这样对我嘛
Anita, don't treat me like this!
你拿鞭子打我好了
Just spank me with your whip.
我是教不了你啦！你好自为知吧！
I can't teach you. You're on your own.
我真的没有用，我什么都不懂
Why am I so useless? I'm so incapable!
我不可以被人看扁的
I can't let people underestimate me!
我要奋斗…
I must work hard...
董骠中了镖，阿苗吃香蕉
Billy paid his bills, Milly's staying still.
没有那么快吃香蕉啊
No! He doesn't stay still so soon!
董骠中了镖，阿苗…阿苗吃香蕉
Billy paid his bills, Milly's... Milly's staying still.
阿苗约埋沙尘超去吃香蕉
Went out with Willie to stay still.
没有这么快吃香蕉啦
No! They don't stay still that soon.
这么大个人了，连话都说不好
I can't even remember a few words at this age. I'm so useless!
董骠阿苗吃香蕉
Billy... Milly stays still.
不要灰心，我先吃点东西
I can't give up! I'll grab something to eat first.
叉烧包！…莲蓉包！叉烧包
Shrimp dumplings! Pork buns! Lotus seed buns!
莲蓉包！叉烧包！叉…叉你个脚！
Pork buns... lotus seed buns! Damn it! I got it all wrong again!
小儿麻痹，再来
Did my legs go loose? Do it again!
还原呀！基本步！你真笨！
And back! Basic steps. I'm so stupid.
再来…
Do it again!
不要学…这个了
Let's not practice this yet.
董骠中了镖，阿苗在吹萧
Billy paid his bills, Milly's making silk.
阿苗…哎吔！真是的，又忘记啦！
Milly... arghll forgot again!
董骠中了镖，阿苗在吹萧  董骠约埋沙尘超
Billy paid his bills... Milly's making silk. Billy met up with Willy. No...
哎吔！一起吃香蕉啦！
No... they went out for chow kwei diu.
董骠中了镖，阿苗在吹萧
Billy paid his bills, Milly's making silk.
骠苗约了沙尘超，一起吃香蕉
Billy and Milly met up with Willy to eat some
然后买马票！买马票！
chow kwei diu and to buy their double q...
董骠中了镖，阿苗在吹萧
Billy paid his bills, Milly's making silk.
骠苗约了沙尘超，一起吃香蕉
Milly made his silk, Billy & Milly met up with Willie
最后买马票，阿超最嚣张  气得董骠似火烧
to eat some chow kwei diu, and to buy their double q. Willy's cocky attitude is lame, bursting
拿香蕉打阿超！不让他一起喝花雕！
Billy into flames. Billy poured his plate of chow kwei diu on Willy
叫阿超吃香蕉，阿苗即刻就撒娇
and refused to buy his double q and told chiu to pay his own bill.
叫他不要打阿超，董骠不慎扭到腰
Milly quickly struck a deal and told him not to hit Willy.
气得阿苗发高烧
Billy slipped and hurt his hips, making it hard for miu to stay still.
哈哈，太棒啦
Wow! Bravo!
乡音都没有啦
Even my accent's gone! Alright!
Nelson
Nelson!
我看你以后还用不用鞭子打人啊
I'm waiting to give you a
看你打不打人啊  Nelson
whip-spanking. Nelson!
打不打人啊
Spanked!
前进它最嚣，哈哈
Chin chun's gotten cocky! Hahaha! Hahaha!
Ta姐她吃香蕉，哈哈哈！
Anita's paid her bill! Hahaha! Hahaha!
请问贵姓芳名
...
这是我的名片
Come for a joyride in my Ferrari whenever you are free.
有空坐我的车去兜风怎么样
...
她哪天都没空
She's busy all day.
我真倒霉
Messed up again.
那个漂亮公子是我先发现的
I saw this handsome young man first!
看起来不怎么样嘛
He looks average.
二号呢？  Sure！No problem
What about number two? Sure. No problem.
三号呢？  Excuse me
How about number three? Excuse me.
还不错呀
- Not bad.
我有点脚软呀！
- My legs are feeling a little numb.
小心一点啊
Relax!
看清楚一，二，三，四啊
Just be sure about the 1, 2, 3, 4.
Hi，Anita，好久不见啦！
Hit Anita! Long time no see!
这位先生是…
And this is...?
刚从美国回来的Nelson Chow
This is Nelson chow. He's just returned from the United States.
Hello！你的手又滑又白呀！
Oh, hello! Your hand is very soft and white.
大家都说我的手好性感啊
Many people have said that I have very sexy hands.
对呀，大家都说她的手最性感啦
Oh yeah! Many people have complimented her sexy hands.
连看相的都说她手淫
Even the fortune teller says her hand looks very obscene.
飞凤姐好可爱，她最爱开玩笑了
You sure know how to poke fun, fei-feng. You really love to kid around.
Nelson，好久不见啦
Long time no see, Nelson.
该怎么样就怎么样
Just do your job and make a fool out of them. Don't mind me.
千万不要顾虑我  女代表来了
Oh! The dog exhibition representative.
Sure！No problem
Sure. No problem!
有点气质好不好
Show me some proper posture, will you?
千万不要让那些下流男人给骗了  知道吗？
Don't just let any random man fall for you. Got that?
喂！你又看上谁了
Hey! Cat got your tongue already?
记住！千万不要跟费安娜身边  那个胖子说话
Don't let that chubby guy standing next to St. Anna talk to you.
什么戴安芬啊？
St. Anna?
她是船王的女儿
She's the daughter of a shipping magnate.
她身边那个胖子就是她的叔叔
The one standing next to her is her god-uncle.
他是行为学的专家
He's a behavioral specialist.
只要跟他说三句话  他就知道你出身如何
He can immediately decipher the origins of anyone who speaks no more than three words to him.
一不小心就会碰到坏人
With your family background, you're easily bound to meet some bad people.
我先帮你摸摸他的底细
Why don't I check his background for you?
干杯     Hello
- Cheers! - Hello
Anita，你好漂亮  Thank you
Anita! You're looking lovely today. Thank you.
这位是…
And this is...?
他是哑巴
He's mute.
董得多，还没请教
...
Chow！Nelson Chow
Chow! Nelson chow.
周生好少在公共场合出现啊？
It appears that you rarely attend these social gatherings.
他刚从美国回来的
He just came back from America.
有人叫我啦，我们过去打个招呼吧
Hello! Someone's waiting for me. Let's walk over.
多聊一会有什么关系？
It's not such a big loss to stay longer for a chat.
周先生在美国从事哪行  写财经的
So, Mr. chow, what do you do in America? I'm a financial columnist.
是以东岸为主还是以西岸为主？
East coast or the west coast?
东方人当然以东岸为主啦！
As a man of the east, of course I stay in the east.
那就是纽约啰
So it's New York!
周先生住在纽约哪一区啊
Which part of New York do you live in?
区…，我一向宁死不屈
Part... just about any part.
这小子每晚都有名女人陪他
He moves around a lot.
所以他是居无定所的
He doesn't settle down anywhere.
他的家是住在Manhattan
But his apartment's in Manhattan.
总督来了，我们过去吧  好…
The governor's here. Let's head over there. Ok.
Miss Fiona Tung  Hello！Nice to meet you
Ms. Fiona tung. Hello! Nice to meet you.
good evening，Mr Tung
good evening, Mr. tung.
Mr Tung，good evening
Very nice to meet you
And Mr…
Chow，Nelson Chow
Chow. Nelson chow.
Mr Chow，How do you do？
Mr. chowt how do you do?
Do...I love you
Do... l love you.
港督先生，很高兴认识你呀！
Very nice to meet you, Mr. governor.
你的普通话讲得非常标准
You speak mandarin very fluently.
哪里…我的腔调是在美国学的
It's not that great. You speak mandarin much better than me.
香港年青人像你这种人材很少
It's very rare to see Hong Kong youth with such a strong command of mandarin.
我觉得你应该留在香港为他们服务
You must stay in Hong Kong. The future of Hong Kong will depend on talented people like you.
Oh！Sure！No problem
Oh! Sure. No problem.
我这样想，香港人应该团结起来
Hong Kong people should know how to speak in mandarin.
吸收合作，打开国际市场
Those who can't speak mandarin, aren't considered Hong Kong people. Haha!
谢谢，谢谢大家鼓励
Thank you! Thanks for the encouragement.
大家好！你好…
Hello, everybody! Hello!
仪态呀！…
Posture!
你看什么看？  没有啊
What are you looking at? Nothing.
你有电话
You've got a phone call.
高佬伟怎么知道我在这里啊
Does beanstalk wai know I'm even here?
不是他！你去接吧
It's not him. Take the call.
绝对有好处的
You've got nothing to lose.
开玩笑，哪一位呀？
Stop kidding around. Who are you?
你把头伸过来不就知道  我是谁了嘛！
You'll know who I am once you stick your head out.
你以为这样打电话很过瘾吗？
So, do you think it's fun giving a phone call like this?
对呀！你不觉得很罗曼蒂克吗？
Yes. Don't you think it's romantic?
Oh！不，我觉得你好驴哦
Oh no! It's very stupid.
我这完全是为了你
I did all of this just
给你个机会
to give you a chance.
我知道你不好意思  在别人面前接近我
I know it must be awkward for you to get closer to me in the public.
傻瓜，不是我不敢接近你
Don't be silly! It's not that I can't get closer to you in public.
而是我觉得你有一点…狐臭啊
It's just that you have a bit of... Body odor.
你好幽默，好会开玩笑
You're so humorous. You sure know how to make a joke.
你是第一个敢这样跟我  说话的男人
You're the first man to ever talk to me like that!
我吃定你啦，ByeBye！  ByeBye！
I'll be sure to hook up with you. Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Hello！     Hi
- Hello. - Hi
Excuse me！
excuse me!
你干什么？这是男厕所呀
Hey! What are you doing?
男人的秘密，我什么没见过呢
This is the mens washroom. There's nothing I haven't seen in a man's privates.
上官小姐，请你放尊重一点
You should behave yourself Ms. shang-kun.
做爱做的事！
Please don't misunderstand.
上官小姐，你千万不要误会呀！
...
我绝对不是那种随随便便  的男人啊！
I'm not that casual!
听你这么说我更爱死你了
Hearing you say that just makes me tingle!
我要定你了
I'm definitely
都不相信香港的女孩子这么色
going to make out with you!
非礼呀…
Rape!
奸！奸！奸！我要奸死你呀！
Rape! Rape! Rape! I want to rape you!
他怎么会说闽南话？
Why would he speak in a chiu chow dialect?
Hi      Hi
Hi! Hi!
这么巧啊  是啊，这么巧？
What a coincidence. Yes. It is a coincidence.
你要出去呀？
Did you step out?
是啊！我出去呀！
Yes, I stepped out.
你回来啦？
So... you came back?
是呀！May I...dance with you？
Yes! May I... dance with you?
My pleasure
My please.
pleasure…
叉烧包，莲蓉包，糯米鸡  你在说什么？
Pork buns... sticky rice... What are you mumbling about?
叉烧包…没有啦
Pork... it's nothing.
我在国外读书读太久了
I craved for pork buns and lotus seed buns while I spent
我好想吃叉烧包莲蓉包而已
many years overseas for my studies.
我们不要跳了好不好
Why don't we stop dancing?
周先生，你可真会装蒜啊
Nelson chowt you've been pretty well disguised.
可惜你的底牌还是被我给揭穿了
However, I've already uncovered your trump card.
你不要胡说八道啊
Mind what you say.
我绝对不会胡说八道
I'm serious.
各位，这位周先生呢
Everybody! This Nelson chow right here...
大家都对他很陌生，不认识他
Is unfamiliar with everyone. Nobody here knows him.
你们知道为什么吗？
Do you know why that is?
其实啊，他根本就是一位
The fact is... he is the son of
原籍厦门的美国华人富商的儿子
an Chinese-American millionaire and a native in the province of chiu chow!
现在美国华人的富商当中
He is one of four Chinese-American millionaires
姓周的一共有四位
bearing the chow family name.
我先不猜他令尊是谁
Now, I won't ask who his father is.
从他手上厚厚的茧
Judging from the knot in his palm,
就可以看出来他根本不是  在美国读书
I can immediately see that he didn't study in America.
而是在英国的剑桥大学毕业
In fact, he graduated at the university of Cambridge in england.
剑桥的学生都会划船的
Every Cambridge students tow boats.
你一定天天划船
You must have rowed every day and night.
所以你的手才有厚厚的茧
So your palm is bound to get the knot.
我一听你讲闽南话就判断
From the moment I first listened to you speak in mandarin,
你一定是一九八二年剑桥大学
I've come to the conclusion that you must have swapped between the
跟厦门大学的交换学生之一
university of Cambridge and the university of Beijing in 1982.
还有啊，你在厦门大学
Another thing! You studied under the tutelage of
跟过东方语言系的欧阳原教授
professor ouyang for eastern languages in the university of Beijing.
所以你才会讲很标准的闽南话
Therefore, you speak mandarin with a heavy northern accent.
对不对？…
Am I correct?
董教授，都被你猜对了
You've made a very accurate estimation, professor tung.
来…我们敬董教授一杯
Alright! A toast for the brilliance of professor tung.
我也敬你一杯
Let me toast for you
我活这么大还没有在这么多人  面前这么威风过
never in my life have I presented myself so well in front of all those people!
你怎么可以跟总督讲这么  标准的普通话
How can you speak to the governor with such a strong command of mandarin?
还可以吧？  干杯！
It's no big deal.
大嘴！
Big mouth!
我今天还没跟你喝过呢！Cheers！
I haven't drank with you today. - Cheers! - Cheers!
我可以请你跳一支舞吗？
Shall we dance?
可以，当然可以啦
Yes. Of course, you can.
叉烧包呀！莲蓉包呀！
Pork bun! Lotus seed buns! Shrimp dumplings!
虾饺呀！叉烧包！莲蓉包！
Sausage roll! Pork buns! Lotus seed buns.
虾饺呀！叉烧包！
Shrimp dumplings and push.
前进…转一圈…！
Spin around and back!
叉烧包！
Pork buns!
今天晚上舞会好多女人  都说她们好喜欢我
There were plenty of women who were impressed with me tonight.
你呢？
So do you like me?
你喝醉啦！
You're drunk!
你说，你喜不喜欢我
Answer me. Do you like me?
不喜欢…！
I don't. I don't like you.
你骗我呀！
You're lying!
我喜欢他？
Would I like him?
不可能的，我不会这么没水准的
Impossible! I wouldn't be so tasteless.
不可能，我是一个这么尊贵的女人
Impossible! I'm a lady of elegance.
怎么可能喜欢这个大傻瓜呢
I couldn't have possibly like this piece of shit.
简直是天下的大笑话
It's such a joke.
可是，他的确很英俊啊
But he is really good-looking.
我是不是喜欢上我自己  送造出来的形象
Could it be that I've fallen in love with the spitting image that I've created?
不对，我也是一个普通的女人
No. I'm just an ordinary woman.
怎么可以戴着面具做人呢
How can I possibly live off my life, wearing a mask?
我喜欢带着个傻瓜，去逛公园
I enjoy taking him out for a stroll to
去买东西
the park and to the mall for shopping.
人只是追求那一刹那的灿烂而已
After all, it's only a momentary glamour that people ask for.
恶心！一刹那的灿烂就能  代表永恒吗？
Stupid! Can that glamour last forever?
我是一个这么尊贵的女人
I'm a woman with taste. How could I take this
怎么可以带着这个家伙到处逛街呢
piece of shit out to walk around Joyce?
Shit！
Shit!
Oh！My god！他实在好性格
Oh my god! He's really hot!
人是感情的动物
Human beings are creatures with emotions.
别怕啊，别人会原谅我的
Nothing to fear. They'll forgive me.
神经病
That's insane!
我这么做，以后还会有谁找  我做形象顾问
Would anyone hire me as an image consultant if I become that cheap?
Shit！我花痴了，我简直是个花痴
Shit! Am I being flirty? I'm being flirty.
我迷失了…
I'm so lost! I'm so lost!
你干什么？
What are you doing?
好漂亮哦，Good morning！
Hey, beautiful! Good morning!
How do you do？
How do you do?
你嘴巴越来越坏了，赶快换衣服吧
Since when did you learn to talk so naughty? Why haven't you changed into your clothes yet?
三分钟换好衣服，下来吃早餐
I'll give you three minutes to get changed and get down here for breakfast.
你干什么，动手动脚的
What are you doing? Trying to get intimate?
干嘛吗？昨天晚上还好好的
...
更年期到了？
Early menopause?
你才更年期呢？  你知道什么叫更年期？
Nonsense! Do you even know what menopause is?
我先接个电话
I'll go answer the call
Hello！
Hello!
你还认得我的声音吗？  声音好熟啊
Do you recognize my voice? Your voice sounds familiar.
为什么都没有找我呢
Why didn't you call me?
Excuse me，等等
Excuse me. Hold on a minute.
Hello！    Nelson！
- Hello! - Nelson!
哪一位？
Who is this?
我是Lychee呀？你有没有空呀？
I'm lychee. Are you busy today?
开玩笑，打错电话了，神经病
Don't kid around. You've got the wrong number, bitch!
Hello！
Hello!
我是上官飞凤！
I'm fei-feng.
Sorry，我约了Lychee买东西呀
Sorry but I've got an arrangement to go shopping with lychee.
我没有空陪你去呀
I have no time for you.
转…！
Spin...
痛死我了
You're killing me.
再来过！
Let's go again!
你闭上你的眼睛  闭上你的眼睛嘛！
Close your eyes. Close your eyes!
好美哦！  你喜不喜欢？
It's beautiful! Do you like it?
我好喜欢，我爱死它了
I love it!
你怎么了？没事吧
What's wrong with you? Are you alright?
我恨我自己生在一个封建的家庭
I hate myself for being born in a feudalistic family.
我妈妈，奶妈跟干妈
My mother, my nanny and my godmother...
她们都要检查过女孩子才准她们进门
They insist on inspecting my girlfriend before they approve a wedding.
简直就是二十年代的思想
It's the sheer thinking of the victorian age.
请问现在这个社会
Could a modern girl possibly
哪一个女孩子肯让人家检查
be able to go through with this?
哪里有会这种事嘛
Big pan!
是的，现在的女孩子多半  都不肯为爱情牺牲
That's right. Nowadays, girls would never sacrifice anything for the sake of love.
可不是吗？  可是我是这个例外
But I'm a complete exception.
你要相信我
You should trust me.
Nelson！  你肯为我牺牲？
Nelson! Would you make sacrifices for me?
你告诉我，你爱不爱我？
Answer me. Do you love me?
这个问题，你叫我怎样回答你呢
How can I answer this question for you?
你说嘛，我要你说呀
Answer me! Answer me!
我…爱死你了
L... love you to death.
你检查吧！
Then, inspect me!
检查！
She's ready for inspection!
Nelson，怎么还不检查呀？
Nelson, why aren't you inspecting me yet?
不是我要检查，是我妈要检查
I'm not doing the inspection. It's my mother who's inspecting you.
你妈？
Your mother?
伯母
Auntie.
这是我干妈，我老妈，我奶妈
This is my godmother. This is my mother. This is my nanny.
妈！这位就是我常跟你提起的  Lychee小姐！
Mother, this is Ms. lychee, the lady I've been talking to you about all day long. Lychee!
她就是Lychee呀？  是呀
So this is lychee? Yes.
她那两颗怎么跟我的一样大呀
She resembles my upper half.
她还有个大屁股
She's even got a big ass.
四姐，屁股大会生孩子  Nelson！
She's very fertile.
奶妈…怎么样？
well? How is she, nanny?
还真材实料呢  是吗？
Definitely a perfect pair. Is that so?
现在流行小针美容
Breast implants are in vogue nowadays.
她是不是打过针的
Could these be artificial?
我告诉你呀，你要是再找不着呀
You better listen! If you can find one again,
我就决定替你娶那个胖妞了
then I'll make the decisions and arrange you to wed the fat girl.
人家聘金要得可少
They don't charge a huge sum for dowry.
妈，你有没有弄错
Are you crazy, mother?
那个胖妞有什么好？
I can't stand that fat girl!
你别那么多意见啦
You shouldn't complain!
这种女人很难找的
It's hard to find girls like that.
她只要三幢房子
She'll marry you on the condition we give her
一千万美金存款就肯嫁了  伯母呀！
three flats and a dowry of $10 million U.S. Auntie!
其实香港有很多好女孩的
There's plenty of nice girls in Hong Kong.
你为什么不睁大眼睛看清楚点嘛
Why couldn't you widen your eyes for a closer look?
还有你呀！如果Nelson能娶到你
And you I'd be glad if Nelson
那我就开心了
can marry a girl like you.
怎么样？     怎么样？
- How about it? - How about it?
羞死人啦！
It's so embarrassing!
那你肯不肯嫁他呢？
Then, would you marry him?
她害羞呀
She's shy.
八姐，你问她…  你来问
Pak ka, do tell! Do tell!
奶妈，你问啦！  又是我
You tell her, nanny! Me again?
这是我们的家规
These are our family rules.
一定要验明正身，处女才能进门
You must have a full body check-up. We can't accept used goods.
喃呒呵弥陀佛…
Amida Buddha!
不过伯母，我小时候最喜欢  骑马和踢腿了
But, auntie... when I was little, I really enjoyed riding on my bicycle
结果就裂了
and do a lot of exercise.
好了…别吵了…
All gone! Pipe down!
不过呢…八姐
But... well...
还是你来问比较好  妈，你来问啦
It'd be better for you to explain, pak ka. You explain, mom.
奶妈，你来问！  又是我
Nanny, you explain! Me again?
你这样的话就很难证明啦
It's very hard to inspect if you do a lot of exercise.
我要再深入检查一下  看能不能生孩子
So well use our hands to inspect if you're fertile.
这样啊？  是啊…快去
Then... Just go...
那…我只好为你牺牲啦！
Then, I'll make a sacrifice for you!
去啦…！牺牲一下好了…！
Go! Make your sacrifice.
我们一起检验啊  不要，我已经检查过了
Only you in the room alone? I think we'll inspect together.
Nelson，你陪我，你陪我  去吧…
Nelson! Come with me. Come with me! So, where are you doing the inspection?
楼上左边第一个房间
Upstairs. In the first room to your left.
你先上去，我去拿检查工具
Head upstairs by yourself first. I'll grab some tools first.
很快，别怕啊，很舒服
It'll be quick! Very comfortable!
你拿什么？  拿家伙
What are you doing? Picking up my tools.
搅什么鬼？
What are you up to?
每一个零件都要拆开仔细地检查
I'm going to take it all apart and stir it around for a look.
现在可以约上官飞凤了
Go make a call to fei-feng right away!
上官飞凤呀，我是Nelson啊！
Shang-kun fei-feng? It's Nelson.
Nelson！干嘛？  没什么啦
Nelson? What's the matter? Nothing.
我干妈，我老妈，我奶妈
My aunt, my godmother and my wet nurse
她们问你明天有没有空啊
asked if you are free tomorrow night.
她们想看看你
She wanted to see you.
没什么，谈谈我们的婚事嘛
They just wanted to eat with you. That's all it is!
Lychee你怎么穿这种衣服啊
Why are you dressed like that, lychee?
你要嫁人吗？
You're getting married too?
奇怪，我穿这样难道要拍戏吗？
That's strange! Does it look like I'm acting in a movie, being dressed like this?
你老是跟我争我喜欢的男人
You're always fighting for the same man I fall in love with.
我对你已经够忍耐了
I've had enough of you.
简直神经病，竟然敢跟我争男人
You're nuts.
再这样下去我可要翻脸了
It's more like you're competing with me.
翻就翻嘛，难道我会怕你呀
If this goes on again, I'll be angry with you.
简直是花痴，你赶快去死吧
Go right ahead! I don't give a damn. You butt-ugly flirt!
我看你才是花痴呢
I say you're out of your mind!
到那边说
We'll talk inside.
对不起，我们姐妹俩有点私事要商量
Sorry! My sister and I have some private matters to discuss.
失陪了
Please excuse us.
跟我争？  你又凭什么跟我争啊
Fighting over a man with me? You're fighting over a man with me?
也不撒泡尿照一照？
What do you think you are?
他不要我，难道会要你吗？
If he doesn't pick me, do you think he'd pick you?
你胸部打针屁股加料
You've had implants on your boobs and ass.
眼睛鼻子哪里没有整过
Which part of your face haven't you done a plastic surgery on?
总比你没得整好得多吧
At least, it's better than you. You can't even be operated on.
医生不是叫你别去了
The doctor says you don't need to come to him.
你说什么？你…
What did you say? How dare you sling mud at me?
你再说…
Talking about me like that, huh?
快把眼睛鼻子捡起来吧
Have you picked up your face yet?
来，我帮你画…
Here! Why don't I sketch it out for you?
干什么？泼妇
What are you doing? You tramp!
Nelson说我会生孩子
Nelson's bringing me to America
所以才会带我去美国的
because he likes the fact that I'm fertile.
你可以生孩子？让我瞧瞧
You? Fertile? Why don't I take a look?
你这种货色送上门去呀
People like you send themselves to their door
他还当你是妓女呢  你…
he treats you like a whore! You
我告诉你，我是很纯洁的
I'll tell you this! I'm clean.
谁知道你有没有长东西呀
...
什么？你竟然说我长东西
You bitch! How dare you accuse me of that?
有没有你自己最清楚啦
Only you would know.
总比你好呀，你全身都是假的
It's much better than you! Everything is artificial!
上面假下面假，都是假的…  小心点
Your boobs are fake. Your ass is fake. Everything is fake. Fake! Value your life!
什么？你敢跟我说小心点
You're telling me to value my life?
你再敢跟我啰嗦我打得你  一边大一边小
Make any commotion again and I'll hit you hard till the size of your boobs are uneven.
我…数一二三你赶快给我滚出去
I'll count from 1 to 3. You'd better get out.
要不然我就踢你出去
If you don't, I'll kick you out.
谁怕谁呀！一、二、三
Like I'm going to believe that! C'mon! 1, 2, 3!
说我整容，说我的胸部是假的
Saying that I have a fake set of boobs and ass, huh?
我不生气你以为我好欺负啊
You're taking me for a nut if I don't flare up!
我说错了，你不要打，你不要打我
I've said it wrong. Don't! Please don't hit me.
你不要打我
Don't!
我要打你踢你到死为止
I'm going to kick you till the size of your ass gets uneven!
我好可怜哦，被Nelson这样整
I'm really miserable! I got set up by Nelson
还要被你打
and I had to take a beating from you.
你不要打啦
Don't!
我还不是跟你一样惨！
I'm just as miserable as you.
我们不能哭，我们不能当众出丑
We shouldn't cry. We shouldn't embarrass ourselves in front of the public.
不错，要保持仪态  不可以让别人瞧不起
That's right. We need to uphold our charm. We can't make ourselves an embarrassment.
各位，我们有重要的事情要宣布
Everyone! We have an announcement to make.
我们决定不嫁Nelson了
We've decided not to marry Nelson chow.
不是他甩我们，而是我们甩了他
He's not dumping us. We're dumping him.
笑什么？
What are you all laughing at?
我有样东西要给大家看的
I've got something to show you girls.
什么？你敢跟我说小心点
Your mother worked hard to raise you.
你再跟我啰嗦，我打得你  一边大一边小
Make any commotion again and I'll hit you hard till the size of your boobs are uneven.
好没仪态哦  说我整容，说我胸部是假的
So embarrass. Saying that I have a fake set of boobs and ass, huh?
我说错了，你不要打  让开…
I've said it wrong. Please don't hit me. Get out of our way!
我好开心呀
I'm so happy!
因为我今天总算报了仇了
Because I've finally got my revenge!
我们要好好庆祝一下
Let's celebrate!
你做得太过份了
You've gone too far
这小子就是你说的Nelson呀？
This is the Nelson you've been talking about?
长得蛮帅的
He's pretty handsome.
个子很高，可惜黑了点
His height is perfect but he is a little over-tanned.
Auntie，你好！
Hello, auntie!
不帮我介绍一下
Why don't you make the introductions?
来，我来介绍！
Here! Let me introduce them to you.
这位是李锦成太太，霍英西太太  你好！
This is Mrs. Lee kam-shing and Mrs. fok ying-sai.
你好！
Hello!
这位是多明尼加驻港名誉领事
This is the honorary councillman of the Dominican Republic consulate in Hong Kong.
如果你要想移民就找  Mr Glanyman！
If you want to immigrate, then you should look for Mr. gladyman.
Mr Glanyman！
Mr. gladyman!
Hello！你好！
Hello! How are you?
我妈喜欢打牌挑女婿！打白板啦！
Mom likes to pick her son-in-law with a game of mahjong. Take out the white board.
Oh！Sure！ 白板呀！Auntie！
Oh! Sure! Here's a white board for you, auntie!
廿八年旧梦重温呀！我地糊
This is the return of a game from 28 years ago.
我当小姐时还糊过一次
I've been waiting for this since I was a girl.
妈，你运气真好
You're amazing, mommy!
我真是太高兴了！
I'm so happy!
Nelson，五十二个筹码
Nelson! That'll be 512 chips.
Auntie，你说打多大的？
Auntie, how much is the wager again?
不多，十万块钱一底
It's just a small wager. $10,000 per round.
你这铺输了五十一万二千块！
So you've lost a total of $512,000 for this game.
这是六十万！
Here's $600,000! It's no big deal.
我今天真是倒霉呀
It's so bad today.
这副牌一张筒子都没抓到，跑哪去了
It's like everyone's opening an orphanage. They've all hid all the circles.
我妈好久没胡牌了
Mom hasn't had a winning hand for a while.
我也好久没糊牌了
Neither have I.
九章啦！小心呀
Three vets visible!
发财，慢着…等一下  碰…
- Fat choi! Wait! - Hold it! Hold it!
我来看看
Let me take a look first.
发财不能打，打西风吧
Can't play fat choi! Western!
我打西风你不介意吧
Do you mind a western wind?
我怎么会介意呢
I don't.
Auntie，你的西风！
Here's a west for you, auntie!
现在的年青人真厉害，还学会了扣牌
Youngsters aren't so friendly nowadays.
不过我不是说你呀
Of course, I'm not referring to you.
我打西风了吗？对不起，我打错了
Did I just take out the west? I hit the wrong tile.
三筒才对
It should be three circles, auntie!
三筒我吃了
It's a high-risk scenario.
十二章自摸都要包
You'll lose a lot if I win from a self-drawn tile.
九筒
Nine circles!
你妈疯了，大家都知道她听发财
Your mother is nuts. All the other players know that she's going for the fat choi.
三筒不能打要包的
Can't play with three circles.
发财总没有人要了吧
I'd guess you can't play with fat choi.
你打发财，我糊了
Fat choi, right? I'm taking it.
好棒哦      好棒哦
- Great! - Great!
三万二，给钱…  三万二，小意思
That'll be $32,000. - $32,000 is no big deal. It was a great loss. - Pay up...
听说最近有匹马跑得很快
There's a really good pony tomorrow. His name is "clever kid".
被人给阉了
He's been castrated.
打牌打牌呀
Play on.
我忘了今天我老公要我到马场去
I forgot that my husband told me to pull the 1st pony today.
怎么办   这样啊
What do I do - well then!
我看我们打完这把牌就不要打了  好…
Let's stop playing after this round. Did you lose a lot?
没什么啦，才七底
Only seven sets.
小意思嘛
It's no big deal.
这把我地糊六条啊
Aren't you going to pull the first pony? Hurry up!
六条！    糊了…
- Six bamboo! - 1'll take it!
等一等，我不是要打，我是要开杠
Hold on! That's not what I'm taking out. I'm making a Kong.
南风     碰…南风
- South! - Pong!
五条
Five bamboo.
六条断了！七条也没用
Six bamboos are all gone. Seven bamboo is useless.
糊了！…      碰…
- I'll take it! - Pong... pong!
打八条呀！当然是这样打嘛
Eight bamboo! There's no better way to play. If I don't take the chicken hand, it'd be worse than being a chicken.
五万
Five character
南风开杠…
Kong on south! Kong!
七条开杠…
Kong on seven bamboo. I'm in for the taking now.
自摸，糊了…
I'm so lucky now! Four doubles,
四番…  什么四番啊？
four doubles... What do you mean four doubles?
是十番啊，傻瓜  十番？
It's ten doubles, silly boy.
十番是多少啊？Auntie
- Ten doubles. - So, what does that equate to? Auntie
就是每人五十二个筹码！
that's 512 per person.
给钱…
Pay up!
给钱…我请大家去吃饭
I'll treat you all for dinner after this. We'll talk at another time.
不枉比生呀！八十万呀！
I'm living with no regrets now! $800,000!
亲爱的同志们，高佬伟，傻鸡
To my beloved comrades, beanstalk wai and
我们得到最后的胜利啦！
silly chicken! We finally have our final victory!
最后吃到大生意啦！
We've finally got to our opportunities!
大生意
Big opportunity...
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我打牌打得有点累
It's nothing. I just got a little tired after the game
出来运动运动
so I thought I'd go out for a little stretch.
真舒服  你赢了八十万，不错嘛
I feel so much better now. It's not so bad to win $800,000.
八十万对我来讲，小意思！
$800,000 is really not a big deal for me.
小意思那把它扔了吧
If it's not a big deal, you might as well throw it out.
No problem！
No problem!
我是开玩笑的！  我可不是开玩笑的
I was only kidding. I'm absolutely serious with you.
八十万对我来说，真的算不了什么
In my eyes, eight hundred thousand dollars is like pocket change for me.
把它扔了
I'll throw it out.
我妈好欣赏你！  是吗？
- My mother has spoken highly of you. - Really?
她说你是我认识的男人当中
She said you were the most well-mannered
牌品最好的
man amongst all of my other boyfriends.
看着我的眼睛！…
Look into my eyes!
告诉我，你从我的眼睛看到什么呢？
What do you see in my eyes?
没有啊
Nothing.
本来就没有啊
There was no such thing.
Fiona，你赶快下来呀
Fiona! Could you come down for a minute?
我有话跟你说
I want to have a word with you.
我下礼拜生日！在船上开舞会
My birthday's coming up next week. I'm having a party at this yacht.
Fiona    来了
- Fiona! - Coming!
Fiona，你真美
Fiona, you're very beautiful.
真危险
Oh! Very dangerous!
同志们，我们发达啦
Dear comrades. Our opportunity.
发达啦
Opportunities...
大生意…发达啦…
Big opportunity...
我今日打牌好棒啊！
...
我发达啦，我走运啦
From now on, I'll be in charge!
高佬伟住几号房？
What is beanstalk wai's room number?
高佬伟呀？十六号房
Beanstalk wai? He's in room 16.
Thank you very much
发达啦…
I'm fit! Very fit!
有鬼？  鬼在哪里啊
Ghost! Ghost? Where is it? Where?
你不要过来…！
Don't come near me!
我过来啦！
I'm coming to you.
你不要过来呀！
Don't come close to me!
我每个月寄四百九十块钱  给你的家人
I pay $490 to your family every month!
你不要害我呀  你说什么呀？
Please don't hurt me! What are you talking about?
高佬伟说你壮烈牺牲啦！  你摸下我，我是活人
Beanstalk wai said you sacrificed yourself. Touch me. I'm still alive.
会痒的
Grab me while you're at it. Having fun yet?
告诉我！高佬伟人在哪里？
Where is beanstalk wai?
前进…！
Chin chun! Chin chun!
不要跑…捉到啦…
You can't escape away from me! I'll get you!
高佬伟
Beanstalk wai!
不要跑，捉到啦…
Don't move! Gotcha! Gotcha!
怎么是你！
Oh! It's you.
好痛啊…你怎么上来的
That hurt. Why did you come here?
施大嘴告诉我你在这里的
Big mouth sze told me that you were here.
你为什么骗我？
Why did you lie to me?
骗你？一点点误会啦
Lie to you? You've got a misunderstanding.
等等啊
Hold on a minute! Hold on!
出去啦…快出去，不要啰嗦  这么扫兴哦
Get out! Get out!
你为什么告诉我傻鸡死了
Why did you tell me that silly chicken died?
那五万块钱大家要拿来平分嘛
We should share the fifty thousand together.
你疯了，你吃里扒外呀
Shut your mouth! Who do you think you are?
你也不想想这些金链子是  从哪里来的
Look at these necklaces you're wearing. Who bought it for you?
原来你是骗我的，哪来的好日子
You lied to me! You deceived me! There is no opportunity you've spoken of
你骗人，你骗我
you lied to me!
前进，你不能怪我，这都是他的主意
None of this is my fault. It was all his idea.
不要说了，你这个臭小子，一肚子坏水
I know! It was you, you damned midget! You damned midget!
是，是我的主意
Yes! It was my idea.
我该死，我撞墙死了算了  我错了，我不应该
I deserve this. I should slam my head on the wall. I shouldn't have. I shouldn't have!
不要这样子
Don't do this! Don't!
我们三个本来一直都是好兄弟
We are good brothers after all.
我今天来本来是要  告诉你们一个好消息
I wanted to give you some good news today.
好消息，什么好消息？
Good news? What's the good news?
我今天打麻将赢了八十万  拿来
I won over $800,000 at a mahjong game. Fork it over!
我本来是要回到家乡给我们  盖幢新房子
I originally wanted to go back to our village and build a new house.
好主意啊    你还说好
Good! That's a great idea! And you still say it's a good idea?
你在我身上不知捞了多少油水
You've taken advantage of me long enough.
以后，你们是你们，我是我
From now on, you live your lives and I'll live mine.
我要拿八十万回到家乡好好享用
I'm going back to the country and live like a king!
跟我无关  八十几万？
- I'm not at fault here! - $800,0007
我拿走我的行李
I'll grab my bag first.
我可以回家乡弄个乡长做一做
Then I can go back to the village and buy the title of village chief
行开
- step away.
前进…
- Chin chun! Chin chun!
你这样不辞而别吗？
Don't just leave us like that
你还记得我们的暗号吗？
do you remember our code?
记得！
I do.
看着我…
Look at me! Look at me!
看着我的眼睛  从我的眼睛，你看到什么？
Look into my eyes. What do you see in my eyes?
看你妈的头！
Your mother!
都是你啦，那么喜欢骗人
You deserved it! Lying to him like that time after time.
Anita，前进呢？
Anita, where is chin chun?
他好像不开心，你别吵他
He's not in a good mood right now. You shouldn't disturb him.
他不开心，我还不开心呢
He's in a bad mood. Well, so am I!
前进
Chin chun!
我再给你十万，你再帮我一次忙
I'll pay you an extra $100,000 to make a fool out of another girl.
那个Fiona，我施公子约她出去
That Fiona! I tried to ask her out on a date but
她居然说她没兴趣
she said she had no interest in me.
你再帮我一次忙，我要报这个仇
I want you to put her into ruins.
你说哪个Fiona？
Are you talking about Fiona?
还有哪个Fiona？
I'm talking about that Fiona!
对不起，我不干！
Sorry. I won't do it.
什么？他跟她什么关系呀
What did you say? What the hell is he doing?
你不好好地想一想
Who the hell do you think you are?
没有我你哪有今天啊
Without me, you wouldn't have become what you are today.
你所有吃的，穿的，住的
All your accomodations including food, clothes and
全部都是我给你的
living expenses
我会叫警察把你送回大陆去的
are completely provided by me!
干嘛
What the hell?
我看你一定是疯了
You must have gone crazy.
你呀，你给我好好地劝劝他  好啦
And you! You better have him convinced right away. That's enough!
忍耐是有个限度的！
There's a limit to tolerance.
我就知道你们两个有问题！
I knew you two had an affair all along.
前进，去拿衣服，我们走
Chin chun, let's pack up. We're leaving.
你们要上哪去？
Where are you going?
奸夫淫妇
You adulterers!
施大嘴，你被Lychee玩是活该的…
You deserved to be fooled by lychee, big mouth sze!
对不起，我失态了，走吧
Sorry. I was ill-mannered just now.
我就知道你们女人一看到男人  就会晕头转向
You women all go crazy on the sight of good-looking men.
我就知道女人不可相信
Women can't be trusted.
我还是找男人帮我的忙
It's better to trust men!
再过两天就是Fiona的生日
Fiona's birthday is coming up in a couple of day.
前进一定会去的
Chin chun will definitely be attending.
你们跟我一块去拆穿他  说他是大陆仔
When the time comes, I want you to come with me and expose his mainlander status.
到时候，这些钱全部是你们的
Then, this money will all be yours.
加十万
I'll raise it by another hundred thousand!
我们情同手足
But he's my best friend.
再加十万
Another hundred thousand.
我们是同乡兄弟
But we came from the same village.
再给你十万！
How about another hundred thousand?
我们是游泳来的
We swam the seas to come here together.
再加十万！
Hundred thousand more!
我们都是龙的传人  高佬伟！
We're descendents of the dragon.
你要想清楚一点呀！
You should think about it, beanstalk wai!
不必想清楚了，再加十万
No need to think about it. I'll give you another hundred thousand.
钱是万能的
Money is everything.
一言为定
Then, it's a deal!
你想干嘛？
What are you doing?
我想亲你，你喜欢我吗？
I wanted to kiss you. Don't you like me?
我绝对不会跟我的学生  发生感情的！
I won't fall in love with my students.
你骗人！
You're lying.
你还是用心的去追Fiona吧！
You should concentrate on wooing Fiona.
朱丽丽，替我订火车票
Lily chu. Book my train ticket for me.
我决定去丝绸之路了
I've decided to travel the silk road.
大概四五个月左右吧！
I'll be away for 4-5 months.
干嘛拆了我的领结
Why did you untie my bow?
一个真正的公子一定要会打领结
A real playboy should be able to tie his own bow.
你看，先要打个结  然后从下面翻上来
First, you tie a knot. Then, you push it back up.
接着呢，就要拉过去，就可以了
After that, you pull it like this. And there, you have it!
没关系！有你天天在我身边  你帮我打
That's okay. With you by my side, you can tie it for me everyday.
你真的不去呀
Are you sure you're not going?
我不太想去！我知道
I'm not going. I know.
我一手训练出来的公子
The fact that the playboy I've personally trained
可以追到最高贵最美的女子
can woo the most beautiful and elegant woman.
我已经很开心了
It really makes me happy.
Thank you！
Thank you!
你开我的车去！
Take my car
我不知道会不会开呀！
I'm not sure if I can drive it properly.
做公子怎么能没有名车呢？
How can you be a playboy without a fancy car?
Good night！
Thank you！
Thank you!
Nelson！    Hello！
- Nelson! - Hello!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!
各位朋友
Dear friends. Attention please!
Attention please！
Attention! Please!
今天呢，是Fiona的生日
Tonight is Fiona's birthday.
我趁这个机会，向大家宣布一件事
I'd like to take the opportunity to make this announcement to everyone.
什么事呀
What's going on?
我妈要给你一个惊喜呀
Mom wants to give you a surprise.
这件事呢，就是Fiona
For me? And that is the official announcement of Fiona's wedding
要跟Nelson Chow先生  今天宣布订婚
engagement to Mr. Nelson chow!
Congratulation！
Congratulations!
恭喜！恭喜  谢谢
Congratulations! Thank you.
Nelson，恭喜你呀  谢谢
Nelson，你怎么了？
Nelson, what's the matter with you?
你妈搞什么呀？
What's your mother up to?
我妈喜欢这样，你不要怪她！
Mom likes it that way so we should let it be.
Fiona，赶快上去啊！
Come up to the stage, Fiona!
Auntie，怎么回事啊？
Auntiet what are you up to?
还叫我Auntie？
Still calling me auntie?
这里是十万股汇丰的股份
Here's 100,000 market share in the bank of Hong Kong.
还有夏威夷的一幢房子
And a house in Hawaii.
你可千万别嫌少啊
Don't begrudge such a small gift.
Auntie，我不能要你的东西呀！
I shouldn't accept this from you, auntie.
这是我送给你们的订婚礼物
Consider it a wedding gift from me to you.
这是你们的订婚戒指
Here's your engagement ring.
赶快替她戴上吧
Hurry up and put it on her.
对了，别忘了亲Fiona一下
Don't forget to give her a kiss. Go now! Go!
Excuse me！Ladies and gentlemen！
Excuse me. Ladies and gentlemen!
我现在要告诉大家一个大秘密
I'd like to share a little secret to everybody.
我们这位Nelson Chow，周公子
The true identity of Nelson chow.
他的真正身份我想大家  恐怕还不知道吧
I'm afraid nobody knows the real identity of him
我现在要告诉大家
I'd like to tell you that
他的本名叫做周前进
his real name is chow chin-chun.
他是个大骗子
He is a big swindler.
什么？你说他是大骗子
You're saying that he's a mainlander?
这真是天大的笑话
He just said he's a mainlander.
各位，你们相信他说的话吗？
Would anyone believe him?
好了…各位，没事了
This little joke is finished. You can all settle down in your seats.
请各位入坐…
Get back to your seat. Please get back to your seats.
这不关我的事，我也不赞成这么做！
Don't look at me! I never agreed to any of this.
是高佬伟逼我来的！
Beanstalk wai forced me into this.
没关系，我自认倒霉
It's okay. I don't mind being exposed.
但是我没有想到，他会为了钱出卖我
But I've never thought for a moment that he would actually betray me for money.
高佬伟，说得好再加二十万
Beanstalk wai, if you say it well, I'll add $200,000 as a bonus.
这是十万定金
Here's $10,000 as a deposit.
各位，你们不要以为我说说而已
I'm serious, everybody.
高佬伟，你告诉他们
Tell them, beanstalk wai.
又有什么笑话呀
What other jokes do you have to share with us?
说！
Tell them!
怎么说？  你不知道怎么说？
I don't know how to say it. You don't? Fine!
好！我问你答！
I'll ask while you answer.
你跟Nelson Chow是不是很熟？
Do you know Nelson chow well?
是
Yes.
他的底细你是不是全都知道  是
Do you know his background? Yes.
你跟他是不是从大陆偷渡过来的
Did you enter these grounds illegally with him?
说啊
Say it...
不是
No!
不是啊…你们大家都有听到  他不是啊
No! We really didn't! You've heard the man!
周先生他是在香港出生的！
Mr. chow was born in Hong Kong.
我才是偷渡过来的
I'm the illegal immigrant here.
周先生对我很好
Mr. chow treats me well.
是他！因为他追不到那个什么娜小姐
It was him! It's because he couldn't impress Ms. Fiona.
就用很多钱来贿赂我
So he bribed me with a lot of money to
叫我冤枉周先生
make an accusation on Mr. chow.
你…你不讲义气…
You've lost your loyalty!
是！我是不讲义气
Yes! I'm not loyal at all.
我这辈子都不讲义气
I've never been loyal in my life!
但是这一次我很够义气
But this time, I'm showing my loyalty.
你…
You...
你这是干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
这些钱就是他用来贿赂我的！
This is the money he used to bribe me with.
现在我不要了
I don't want it anymore.
还给你…
I'll give it back to you. Take it back!
对不起
Sorry!
我从大陆游泳过来，举目无亲
I came here by swimming. I had no family.
幸亏碰到周先生，他一直照顾我
Luckily for me, I met Mr. chow. He's always been watching over me,
他提携我，指导我
giving me opportunities, and guiding me.
因为我贪心
It's because of my greed
竟然被那个施大嘴用肮脏钱所引诱
that I allowed big mouth sze to seduce me with his dirty money.
我不是人，我对不起你
I am not a man. I'm doing you an injustice.
我错啦…  你不要这样
I'm w rong!
我错啦…
Don't!
你不要这样…
From now on,
我希望你以后
I hope you will disregard me for the
就算我当乞丐也不要理我
rest of your life. Even if I am begging for money.
高佬伟
Beanstalk wai
还记得我们的暗号吗？
do you still remember our code?
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难
"Brave all difficulties
我们要发达
to fight for victory!"
周先生，你不要理我们这种人
Mr. chow, just ignore these people.
就当我们是神经病
These people are crazy.
不会的，你还是我的好朋友  我的好兄弟
No! You're still my good friend. You're still my good brother.
各位，我觉得我戴着假面具骗你们
Everyone! I feel that I've been spent far too long, deceiving you with this mask.
我觉得好累，也好傻
I'm fed up with this. It's stupid!
我更不会因为虚荣而不认  这两个好朋友，好兄弟
I won't even deny those two men are my good friends in order to continue with this silly charade.
高佬，傻鸡
Beanstalk wai, silly chicken!
各位，这两个都是我的  好朋友，好兄弟
Everybody! These two are my best friends. My brothers!
我们是一起长大的，而且…
We've been playing together since we were kids.
我们一起游泳过来
We even swam our way to come here.
我们是大陆仔
We're mainlanders!
不过，我们也都跟你们一样
But you and I are all the same.
是中国人，我们是龙的传人
We're Chinese! We're all descendents of the dragon!
你胡说，你骗我
You're lying to me!
就算你不高兴我妈单方面宣布订婚
Even if you resent my mother's unilateral engagement announcement,
你也不需要说这种话
you don't need to spread a lie.
我不管你是谁，我都会喜欢你
I don't care who you are. I love you so much!
我要嫁给你
I'll marry you no matter what!
Fiona，就算我是周公子  我也不会娶你呀
Fiona, even if I was rich, I won't marry you.
为什么？
Why?
因为我喜欢的是Anita！
Because I'm in love with Anita.
不会的！…  对不起
It can't be! I'm ss 0 rry!
玩笑开够了，你也应该顾顾她的面子
Joke's over. She's a gentle girl.
过去哄哄她吧
Go comfort her!
你可以证明你的身份吗？
Is there any way you can prove your identity?
可以
Yes
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
下定决心，不怕牺牲
"Make up your mind, have no fear of sacrifices."
排除万难，我们要发达，下定…
"Brave all difficulties to fight for victory!"
你们不要唱了！
Stop singing!
你们不信是吗？兄弟们
Still not convinced? Brothers!
好脏啊
- So dirty! - Security!
警卫
Security!
警卫，快点来呀…把他们带走
That's right! Arrest those men...
董太太，什么事呀
What's the matter, Mrs. tung?
不是他，是他
Not him! But them!
这个  怎么是我
This one
- why me? No! Don't! - Don't gripe!
少啰嗦  你不可以把我丢下海呀
Don't dump me into the seal!
姐妹，上！
Let's go, sisters!
你怎么可以这样对我
How can you treat me like this.
你下去吧！
Jump into the seal!
原来他就是大嘴宴会上那个臭男人
So Nelson was that mainlander!
你还不走呀，船长，带他们走
Why don't you leave? Captain, take them away!
拜拜
Bye!
Nelson！Nelson！
Nelson! Nelson!
Fiona，不要这样子啊
Fiona, don't! Just let it be.
不好了，戒指还在我这！
Crap! I've left my ring there.
对不起  你干什么？
Sorry!
你不是喜欢Anita吗？
Didn't you say you liked Anita?
就用这个戒指向她求婚
Then you can take this ring to propose
省事多了嘛
to her and you can save a lot of money.
还是你聪明
Good point!
Anita！Anita呢？  Anita！
- Anita! - Anita! Where's Anita?
谁叫你玩到天亮才回来呀
Why did it take you the entire morning to come back from partying?
她走了
She's already left!
上哪去了？说啊
Where did she go? Tell me!
她坐六点半的火车去游丝绸之路了
She took the 6:30 train to head over to the silk road.
马上就六点半啦！
It's close to 6:30!
快，快去追她回来呀
Alright! Let's go pick her up!
莫非我的幻觉这么灵验？
Perhaps my illusions are getting stronger.
Anita呀Anita呀！  你快要得神经病了
Anita! Anita! You're going out of your mind.
不过说真的，如果他开车来追我的话
But to be frank about it, if that was really him chasing after me with the car,
我一定会嫁给他
I will definitely marry him.
就算是真的也不行啦
It's no use to think about it even if it were true.
这班车是直达车，中间不停的
This is a one-way express. There won't be any stops.
Anita！
你怎么会来的
What are you doing here?
开心，我们都解决啦！  对呀
Of course, we're happy! We've finally let it out! Yeah!
恭喜你当上船王的女婿了！
Congratulations on becoming the shipping magnate's son-in-law!
我告诉全世界了，我们是大陆仔  对呀
I told the whole world that we're all mainlanders! Yeah!
干嘛这么做？
Why did you do that?
因为我要你嫁给我  对呀
Hoping that you'd marry me. and the dog exhibition representative?
是啊，是一见钟情
Yes, it was love at first sight.
可是我天天跟你在一起
But I've already deeply fallen in love
我已经对你日久生情了
with you since I face you everyday.
不要再亲来亲去了  我们快到罗湖啦！
Stop the chit-chattering, you guys! We're getting close to luo-hu!
我才不管这些
What's that got to do with me?
我们没有身份证
We have no l.D. Cards!
这样，我们会不会被抓去  壮烈牺牲？
Then, we'll be sacrificed.
我要先答应嫁给我
...
你们先跳车啦  我现在才了解你
Hurry up and get out of the train! I can't believe this!
原来你重色轻友！  我们是好兄弟！
So you value sex more than friendship. Aren't we brothers?
Anita，嫁给我吧
Marry me, Anita!
你还考虑什么
Why are you still hesitating?
妹妹，又不是叫你马上嫁给他
Sister, it's not like you're going to marry him right here and now.
你先答应他嘛  是啊
Just say yes to him. Exactly!
好吧，我暂时答应你
Very well! I'll say yes for now.
我有空再嫁给你，你现在赶快走吧
We'll get married once I have free time. Go right away! Go!
谢谢你Anita  快走
- Thanks, Anita! - Get out of there!
好了…她答应了  快走…
- Alright! She said yes already. Let's leave! - Let's go, chin chun!
劳燕分飞，早生贵子，拜拜…
I wish you two the best in your marriage. May you be blessed with children soon!
你还记得我们的暗号吗？
Do you still remember our code?
SevenEIeven
Seven eleven!
等我！
Wait for me!
谁把它打开的
Who opened the door?
关上啦
Close it back!
先生，花借用一下
Hey, mister! Can you lend this to me for a second?
这我扫墓用的
I need these flowers for a cemetary visitation.
我很快就还给你了
I'm just borrowing it for now.
你怎么没跳车呢
Why haven't you jumped from the train yet?
我要跟你一齐跳啊！
If I wanted to jump, I would've jumped with you.
你现在有空？  闲得很
Are you free yet? Yes, I'm very free.
你愿意嫁给我做老婆吗？
Will you marry me and become my wife?
我愿意
I willl
就算我被抓你也愿意
even if you'd get arrested?
我现在要告诉你一个秘密
I'll tell you a little secret.
我已经向Glanyman买了一本护照
I've already bought a passport from that gladyhan fella.
我已经是正式的多米尼加公民了
I'm now officially a citizen of the Dominican Republic.
你骗我！
Hey! You tricked me!